<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Deep Text</title>
    <link>http://entish.org/deeptext/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Deep Text</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2022 21:17:05 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://entish.org/deeptext/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Chef</title>
      <link>http://entish.org/deeptext/posts/chef/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2022 21:17:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://entish.org/deeptext/posts/chef/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Chef was an experimental case-based planning project developed by Kris Hammond. It used the domain of cooking as a way to explore the use of case-based reasoning in planning. A &amp;ldquo;micro&amp;rdquo; version of Chef can be found in Inside Case-Based Reasoning1 (ICBR).
The case study in ICBR considers plan adaptation, failure prediction, and failure repair. A recipe for stir-fry beef and green beans is adapted for beef and broccoli, but the broccoli comes out soggy, because it has been cooked in too much broth from the beef.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advices</title>
      <link>http://entish.org/deeptext/posts/advices/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2022 16:47:57 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://entish.org/deeptext/posts/advices/</guid>
      <description>Business Advice from a young robot to an aspiring entrepreneur I ask the OpenAI brain for advice on how to run Twitter&amp;rsquo;s Verified Accounts. The context is Elon Musk&amp;rsquo;s recent takeover of Twitter and the debacle that ensued when he allowed any account to be verified for $8 per month.
My prompt was this, up to Advice:
I need some advice. I am the new CEO of a major social media platform.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome</title>
      <link>http://entish.org/deeptext/posts/welcome/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2022 13:20:31 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://entish.org/deeptext/posts/welcome/</guid>
      <description>Hello! The following welcome message was written by OpenAPI[1], given the following prompt:
Write a short friendly welcome paragraph, describing the new blog and what it&amp;#39;s about: The use of deep text models. Paragraph: Welcome to my new blog on deep text models! In this blog, I&amp;rsquo;ll be discussing the use of deep text models in natural language processing. I&amp;rsquo;ll be exploring the various benefits and applications of these models, as well as some of the challenges involved in working with them.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
