<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Personal and family on Will&#39;s Whims</title>
    <link>http://example.org/categories/personal-and-family/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Personal and family on Will&#39;s Whims</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2012 03:30:38 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://example.org/categories/personal-and-family/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Moving to Michigan</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2012/09/05/moving-to-michigan/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2012 03:30:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2012/09/05/moving-to-michigan/</guid>
      <description>Just a short note — this is a very busy week for me. I am preparing to return to live in Michigan, after eight months or so in California. I’ll still be working for Wordnik — thank God and Tony Tam — but mostly working remotely. I’ll be coming to California once a month, as I have done in the past prior to working for Wordnik.
Also, my son Mark has just moved from China and is staying with me this week.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leroy Herron</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2011/11/06/leroy-herron/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Nov 2011 06:10:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2011/11/06/leroy-herron/</guid>
      <description>When I was in junior high school at Burton Junior High School — that is, grades seven and eight — Mr Leroy Herron was a very important man in my life. He was a school counselor, and a coach for the basketball team. He was also the sponsor of the Human Relations Club, a club created to get black kids and white kids like me to learn more about what I now might call anti-racism, but then we mostly called non-discrimination.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I am a Wordnik</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2011/11/04/i-am-a-wordnik/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2011 04:14:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2011/11/04/i-am-a-wordnik/</guid>
      <description>This week, I started as the lead engineer for Wordnik‘s analytics platform. Except I get a little antsy about the term “engineer,” so I asked them to make my title “Lead, Analytics Platform.” It’s a real pleasure to work with the Wordnik team so far–super excited to be working with Tony Tam and Erin McKean, and also former Powersetters Colin Pollack and Robert Voyer. When Robert joined Wordnik over a year ago, I badgered him into getting me an interview–it’s only now that it’s come to fruition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Remembering Miss Mullens</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2011/10/07/remembering-miss-mullens/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2011 15:33:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2011/10/07/remembering-miss-mullens/</guid>
      <description>It’s Ada Lovelace Day and we are encouraged to write about women who were significant in getting us involved in Science and Technology.
I remember my Junior High Geometry teacher, Miss Mullens. She was very, very short, kind of shy, but very funny — a classic geek, really, now that I think of it (geek, of course, being a term of praise here, not a negative thing).
Junior High school geometry, for me, was mostly about learning to do proofs — classic Elements of Euclid stuff.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ʬ</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2011/06/08/%CA%AC/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2011 01:52:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2011/06/08/%CA%AC/</guid>
      <description>I discovered “extended IPA” symbols today, including ʬ (smacking your lips). Which I think would be an awesome symbol for “will/whim.”
ʬFather’s Day is coming, ʬ.net is available, but my family is not geeky enough to get it for me…</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Singing with</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2011/05/02/singing-with/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2011 22:13:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2011/05/02/singing-with/</guid>
      <description>This weekend my good friend Samuel Sommers and I traveled south to sing shape note music. It’s Sam’s usual practice to go south on the first Sunday in May and the Saturday before to sing in Huntsville, Alabama on the Saturday and then in Dutton, Alabama for the Dedication Sunday at Shady Grove church, and he graciously invited me along.
The massive storms and numerous tornadoes that hit Alabama changed our plans.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Christmas 2010 Annual Reflections</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2010/12/24/christmas-2010-annual-reflections/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Dec 2010 19:53:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2010/12/24/christmas-2010-annual-reflections/</guid>
      <description>Our annual Christmas letter.
Some years are hinge years; a door swinging from one place to another. 2010 has been a hinge year for us—Jane, Mark, Will and Bess Fitzgerald, with Jane and Mark shifting life stages and transitions for the church that meets in our home. Along the way, though, we’ve had many joys and normal engagements. Here is a bit of the way life has swung for us this year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Computer-assisted friendship</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2010/12/10/computer-assisted-friendship/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Dec 2010 02:03:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2010/12/10/computer-assisted-friendship/</guid>
      <description>Computer-assisted friendship Will Fitzgerald
A response to “Faux Friendship,” by William Deresiewicz 1
Deresiewicz decries social networking sites, especially Facebook, especially in the way that relationships between users of Facebook are called “friends.” Writing a status message is “like pornography.” We have no time for stories. Our relationships are commercialized. We are overwhelmed with the number of false friends. Facebook “seduces” us. It’s a “mirage.” Facebook friends are simulacra of friends.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>e-fast</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2010/02/16/e-fast/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2010 13:52:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2010/02/16/e-fast/</guid>
      <description>For Lent, I’ve decided to refrain from recreational checking of weblogs, Facebook and Twitter, starting February 17 until Easter Monday, April 5, 2010. I may be writing some weblog posts, and updating Facebook notes (and perhaps status), but after today, don’t expect to hear from me much except via the old ways, such as the Tele-Phone, Facsimile Transmission, and E-Mail. And F2F, of course.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Were children again: Report from Camp Fasola, 2009, Session 1 (Adults Emphasis)</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2009/06/20/were-children-again-report-from-camp-fasola-2009-session-1-adults-emphasis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2009 15:39:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2009/06/20/were-children-again-report-from-camp-fasola-2009-session-1-adults-emphasis/</guid>
      <description>At nearly the last minute, Tom Malone suggested that we drive down to Camp Fasola on the Sunday before Camp began in the evening, and return on Thursday, the last day of Camp. I had to work on Friday (“Work—the curse of the singing class,” quipped Richard Schmeidler at dinner one day), and Tom is in the midst of a move back east. So, it was convenient to do this—as if driving 13 hours one way is anyone’s idea of ‘convenient.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Delays</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2008/12/01/delays/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2008 02:23:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2008/12/01/delays/</guid>
      <description>I’m sitting in the airport at O’Hare after the longest plane taxi ride I can remember. It doesn’t really matter how long it took since the flight left late, arrived late, and I have even longer to wait to get on a flight to Seattle. I was supposed to be in Seattle this morning, but a mix-up on tickets (that was my own fault) meant I couldn’t leave until this evening.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kalamazoo to Sitka?</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2008/09/16/kalamazoo-to-sitka/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2008 11:56:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2008/09/16/kalamazoo-to-sitka/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been thinking about traveling to Sitka, Alaska using my frequent flyer miles. But here’s what Northwest suggests a trip would look like there-and-back-again:
And that’s just to get to Juneau! I guess I won’t be going to Sitka. Unless Sarah Palin is offering rides.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A few personal notes …</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2008/07/21/a-few-personal-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2008 17:38:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2008/07/21/a-few-personal-notes/</guid>
      <description>It’s been too long since my last update, but life has been busy, especially with the Microsoft purchase. But a few notes:
 I enjoyed singing Sacred Harp at the Michiana and Kalamazoo annual singings this weekend, and James Nelson-Gingerich gave me the *first* copy of the print version of 26th edition of the Harmonia Sacra for my work on the Harmonia Sacra website. I’m looking forward to a family reunion of all my brothers (five of us!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who acquired Powerset?</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2008/07/01/who-acquired-powerset/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2008 19:27:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2008/07/01/who-acquired-powerset/</guid>
      <description>microsoft acquires powerset</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mark’d</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2008/06/28/markd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jun 2008 00:38:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2008/06/28/markd/</guid>
      <description>A response to Mark‘s tagging me.
Seven factz about me:
 Will Fitzgerald didn’t use a computer until he was 23. It had cards. It is difficult for Will Fitzgerald to refer to himself in the third person. Despite his descriptivist linguistic training, Will Fitzgerald tries to distinguish ‘between’ and ‘among’. Will Fitzgerald was known as “Bill” until he was 33. Will Fitzgerald has half of a house named in his honor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You ain’t seen nothing yet</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2008/05/12/you-aint-seen-nothing-yet/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 May 2008 15:20:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2008/05/12/you-aint-seen-nothing-yet/</guid>
      <description>Who invented the wireless telephone?
It’s been 100 years since “American inventor and Kentucky melon farmer” Nathan B. Stubblefield received the patent for the first wireless cell phone (UK Telegraph article, via Mirabilis).
Today, the company I work for, Powerset, launched its search product for general public use at powerset.com. It’s a really cool search and browsing engine for Wikipedia, with lots of information gleaned from the Freebase project as well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Canoeing the Kalamazoo River: Goose Lake to Twin Pines Campground</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2008/05/04/canoeing-the-kalamazoo-river-goose-lake-to-twin-pines-campground/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 May 2008 10:01:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2008/05/04/canoeing-the-kalamazoo-river-goose-lake-to-twin-pines-campground/</guid>
      <description>Bess has this Grand Plan: to canoe the Kalamazoo River from its headwaters (more or less) to Lake Michigan, and to do it in parts. Yesterday, the Grand Plan commenced. She and I drove to the Twin Lakes Campground near Pulaski Michigan, waking the attendants at 10 am, who dropped us off up river. Our river canoeing skills are rusting (well, mine were never very good to start with), but we managed to stay dry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A day off</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2008/05/01/a-day-off/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2008 20:56:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2008/05/01/a-day-off/</guid>
      <description>I have a couple of days off, so I’m writing a bit on ‘a simple desire’, hanging out with Bess and Jane, uploading MP3 of the afternoon session of the 2008 Golden Gate singing to my website, and watching a waterboarding video.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Foul shots</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2008/04/05/foul-shots/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Apr 2008 16:05:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2008/04/05/foul-shots/</guid>
      <description>I talked to my brother Dave on the phone today, and we agreed that we haven’t played basketball in 300 years. But we have a hoop in the backyard, and I’ve decided to try to get ‘good’ at shooting foul shots. The advantage of foul shots, of course, is that you don’t have to move very much.
My first try was abysmal: 11/50. Yesterday was worse: 10/50. Today, almost, but not quite, not terrible: 19/50.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Happy 77th Birthday, Dad</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2008/02/27/happy-77th-birthday-dad/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2008 02:30:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2008/02/27/happy-77th-birthday-dad/</guid>
      <description>It was my father’s birthday today, and we visited him at the nursing home this evening. We called several of my brothers and even got through to them. Steve complained that I haven’t been writing much in my weblog–guilty as charged, but more than you write in yours, Steve!
Dad has swallowing problems, so we couldn’t bring him cake, but he’s recently been able to eat toast, so we brought our toaster and home made flax bread.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Merry Christmas</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2007/12/25/merry-christmas-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Dec 2007 04:37:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2007/12/25/merry-christmas-2/</guid>
      <description>Merry Christmas, where-ever you are.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Christmas 2007 newsletter</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2007/12/17/christmas-2007-newsletter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2007 15:09:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2007/12/17/christmas-2007-newsletter/</guid>
      <description>In case you’d like to read our Christmas 2007 newletter…</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Traveling kindness</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2007/11/22/traveling-kindness/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2007 02:48:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2007/11/22/traveling-kindness/</guid>
      <description>I had a short article published in our local paper, the Kalamazoo Gazette:
 It was New Year’s Eve, and things were finally starting to go right. Our car had broken down outside Forsyth, Ga., on Christmas Eve, and we had had to hitchhike to northern Florida to visit my mother, leaving our car at a garage for repairs. When we got back to Forsyth, the repair shop declared even more repairs were necessary, and we had to ask my wife’s parents to wire us some money.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RIP, David G. Lockwood</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2007/10/18/rip-david-g-lockwood/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Oct 2007 21:37:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2007/10/18/rip-david-g-lockwood/</guid>
      <description>David G. Lockwood has died, reports the Linguist List.
David Lockwood was one of my professors when I did my degree in linguistics at Michigan State in the 70’s. He was (and remained, I think) an adherent of “stratificationalism,” a kind of constraint-based network theory of language. His classes were the closest I had to mathematical (remember, this was in the heyday of symbolist linguistic theory). I also took historical linguistics, structural (descriptive) linguistics and phonology from him.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Changing my name</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2007/08/18/changing-my-name/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Aug 2007 22:45:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2007/08/18/changing-my-name/</guid>
      <description>I was born William Alan Fitzgerald. Fitzgerald, of course is my family name, but I don’t have any real connections to ‘William’ or ‘Alan.’ My dad sometimes says I was named after my Uncle Allen, but if so, why isn’t my middle name spelled as he spells it? It doesn’t make sense.
So, as of now, I am changing my name.
I want a name that’s different. Really different. Different all the time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Glory to rival the sun</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2007/08/07/glory-to-rival-the-sun/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Aug 2007 03:51:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2007/08/07/glory-to-rival-the-sun/</guid>
      <description>This past weekend, Bess, Jane and I attended the 50th anniversary of the founding of Reba Place Church, the church we attended in the 90’s when I was in graduate school and for a few years afterwards. Saturday was spent going though a decade by decade retrospective. Reba began as, essentially, a commune in the 50’s and experienced explosive growth through the 60s and 70s. They allowed non-communal members in the 80s and there were many aftershocks of many of the communal members becoming everyday variety congregational members.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Distantly related to a giant sloth</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2007/07/16/distantly-related-to-a-giant-sloth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jul 2007 12:15:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2007/07/16/distantly-related-to-a-giant-sloth/</guid>
      <description>My wife’s cousin, David Oren, has been searching for evidence of the existence of the mapinguary, a “giant slothlike monster of the Amazon.” The San Francisco Chronicle published an article on it last Sunday.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A new home</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2007/07/12/a-new-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jul 2007 00:14:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2007/07/12/a-new-home/</guid>
      <description>We closed on a new home yesterday; our new address will be (as of July 19):1219 Grand AvenueKalamazoo, MI 49006 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A singing vacation</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2007/07/10/a-singing-vacation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jul 2007 03:22:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2007/07/10/a-singing-vacation/</guid>
      <description>II can’t do justice to the vacation time we were privileged to have last week, but I wanted to write down a few things, even if it’s just for our own memories in the future.
The basic goal: go to Camp Fasola, a singing camp put on by the Sacred Harp Music Association, now in its fifth year. Dear wife Bess suggested we go, and so she, I, and our daughter Jane, along with two of Jane’s friends (Rachel and Emma) headed down to Alabama.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Great Father’s Day</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2007/06/18/great-fathers-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jun 2007 04:46:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2007/06/18/great-fathers-day/</guid>
      <description>Hmm, the text of my Father’s Day post is gone … sufficient to say that I had a great Father’s Day. My son Mark took me out to Foreign Cinema, a very nice restaurant in San Francisco, where they show foreign films on a drive-in-like screen, but indoors. The food and the conversation were great.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Midwest convention</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2007/05/29/midwest-convention/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2007 04:44:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2007/05/29/midwest-convention/</guid>
      <description>Darrell Swarens has posted a video of the Chicago Sacred Harp Singers’ Midwest Convention, held over the weekend. The video shows James Eldridge leading Panting for Heaven. It shows his skill and composure at leading despite his young age. It also shows the beautiful setting of Ida Noyes Hall at the University of Chicago. The discerning and knowing eye will see lots of midwest and nationwide Sacred Harp worthies around the square.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kelly (and Susan) Clark</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2007/05/07/kelly-and-sue-clark/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 May 2007 07:36:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2007/05/07/kelly-and-sue-clark/</guid>
      <description>Sunday evening, Bess, a number of friends, and I went to hear Calvin professors Kelly Clark (philosophy) and Steve Matheson (biology) speak on “God after Darwin, Dawkins, and Dennet” at the Church of the Servant in Grand Rapids. Kelly has been a friend of Bess’s since high school, and Susan Ford Clark, Kelly’s wife, shared an apartment with Bess their senior year–in fact, Kelly and Susan, and Bess and I, were married on the same day in the same church (at different times).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Democracy in action</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2007/05/07/democracy-in-action/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 May 2007 07:22:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2007/05/07/democracy-in-action/</guid>
      <description>My dad loves to vote. He once paid to take a taxi just so he could vote in a local school election. He was very disappointed that he couldn’t vote in Michigan’s last gubenatorial race, so we worked hard on getting him registered in Kalamazoo township, where his nursing home is. Well, mostly this was done by Amy, the social worker at his nursing home, Tendercare of Westwood.
In turns out that it’s a school election that will be Dad’s first Kalamazoo-area vote.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Shyster Saga</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2007/05/01/the-shyster-saga/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2007 03:44:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2007/05/01/the-shyster-saga/</guid>
      <description>On the Fasola discussions list (a list for discussions about the history and practice of shape note singing), I wrote the following paragraph about a crooked ‘singing master’ (that is, a 18th or 19th century singing school teacher):
 On the other hand, I did recently read (in the Historic Missouri Newspaper Project online archives) a warning advertisement for one singing master who was a shyster and who absconded with funds collected for the school and for printing flyers, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two small occasional works</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2007/04/23/two-small-occasional-works/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Apr 2007 05:54:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2007/04/23/two-small-occasional-works/</guid>
      <description>This has been a delightful weekend. On Saturday, I attended the Golden Gate Sacred Harp singing in San Francisco (with a nice Après-chant at Philip’s house, nicely described by Linda, who also has pictures of the singing). In the morning today, Jeff Shrager took me to see redwoods and banana slugs and tidepools, capped by some nice bluegrass music at a cafe. Worship at Sojourners was also good.
Back in Michigan, I missed some cool things happening.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Attn: Dan Fitzgerald</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2007/03/30/attn-dan-fitzgerald/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2007 22:46:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2007/03/30/attn-dan-fitzgerald/</guid>
      <description>Signs of the Apocalypse:
[Reporting on NCAA tournament pool at Powerset]: Will Fitzgerald is now in the lead, followed by Lukas, then Dave. If Georgetown wins Dave Simpson is in VERY good shape.
Here is the Breakdown going into the final four:
Will Fitzgerald: 78 (teams left: FLA, OSU) Lukas B: 77 (teams left: FLA, OSU, G’Town) Dave S: 76 (teams left: FLA, OSU, G’Town) Richard H 1: 62 Richard H 2: 59 Ryan F: 57 Chris K: 56</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How short the time! How frail the state!</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2007/02/14/how-short-the-time-how-frail-the-state/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2007 16:48:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2007/02/14/how-short-the-time-how-frail-the-state/</guid>
      <description>Death, like an overflowing stream, Sweeps us away; our life’s a dream, An empty tale, a morning flow’r, Cut down and withered in an hour.
Our age to sev’nty years is set; How short the time! How frail the state! And if to eighty we arrive, We’d rather sigh and groan than live.
Teach us, Oh Lord, how frail is man; And kindly lengthen out the span, Till a wise care of piety Fit us to die and dwell with Thee.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Happy Valentines Day, Jane!</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2007/02/14/happy-valentines-day-jane/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2007 04:00:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2007/02/14/happy-valentines-day-jane/</guid>
      <description> Kittens! Puppies! Puppies! and Kittens!  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First KMenno worship service</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2007/01/29/first-kmenno-worship-service/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2007 07:25:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2007/01/29/first-kmenno-worship-service/</guid>
      <description>The first worship service of the Kalamazoo Mennonite Fellowship happened yesterday–five people (including Bess, Jane and me) were present. Jane revealed the ‘psalm, hymn or spiritual song’ she’s been keeping secret: O Come, O Come Imannuel. I began a series on the Confession of Faith in a Mennonite Perspective; the first article is on God (I spoke in favor). Bess made chili and bean soup for afterwards; one participant, Carolyn, brought her own can of soup just in case the soup being served contained beans, which was wonderfully prescient of her.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>National Save Darfur Tour: Hip Hop Benefit Concert at MSU</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2007/01/22/national-save-darfur-tour-hip-hop-benefit-concert-at-msu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2007 16:45:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2007/01/22/national-save-darfur-tour-hip-hop-benefit-concert-at-msu/</guid>
      <description>News article Concert info – look under music
 n the Student Assembly meeting of the Associated Students of MSU, held Nov. 30, the Assembly agreed to vote for a bill that will create on-campus education activities to help encourage students’ action against the genocide in Darfur. The activities have been planned by the MSU Chapter of worldwide student network “Students Taking Action Now: Darfur.” “I am confident that the voting process will favor support for the ASMSU and S.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kalamazoo Mennonite Fellowship now forming</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2007/01/11/kalamazoo-mennonite-fellowship-now-forming/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2007 21:07:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2007/01/11/kalamazoo-mennonite-fellowship-now-forming/</guid>
      <description>Simplicity. Service. Peace. Worship. Community. Jesus.
The Kalamazoo Mennonite Fellowship is now forming.
Starting January 28, 2007. 10:30 to noon, Sundays, with soup supper to follow. Bring a psalm, a hymn or spiritual song.
For more information, contact Will or Bess Fitzgerald.
269.381.4264 info@kmenno.orgwill.fitzgerald@gmail.com http://www.kmenno.org 1207 W. Maple St., Kalamazoo, MI 490081219 Grand Avenue, Kalamazoo, MI 49006
(Complete with Craiglist ad!)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Infinite will</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2007/01/05/infinite-will/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jan 2007 19:45:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2007/01/05/infinite-will/</guid>
      <description>This sort of just happened today, while initiating a video conference between the Powerset mothership and the Kalamazoo complex (i.e., my basement).
Jeff Shrager pointed his camera at the projector screen, and made iChat full screen. So, I guess I’m talking to myself here. Talk about an echo chamber!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jane Oren Wend</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2006/12/22/jane-oren-wend/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Dec 2006 03:22:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2006/12/22/jane-oren-wend/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been trying to find the right words for this, but I haven’t been able to. So I must just plunge in.
Last Saturday morning, my mother-in-law, Jane Oren Wend, died. Today was her burial and memorial service. The service was held at First Presbyerian Church in Kalamazoo, Michigan Wayne Conner read words by Jared (“Jerry”) Wend, her husband who died about three years ago, inviting people to remember, grieve and live in hope.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>White and nerdy</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2006/10/08/white-and-nerdy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2006 02:35:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2006/10/08/white-and-nerdy/</guid>
      <description>How White and Nerdy Are You?
(At least I only took a white and nerdy quiz; didn’t make it up.)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A visit up north</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2006/10/07/a-visit-up-north/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Oct 2006 01:33:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2006/10/07/a-visit-up-north/</guid>
      <description>Bess and I made a quickie visit “up north” to see two of my brothers and their families. Here are a few pictures from our visit to Ed’s house.
Ed just bought a pretty cool chipper–he does a lot of part time work cutting down trees, and chipping them.
Even cooler, Ed bought an old firetruck from the Baldwin fire department. He hopes to put a pick on it to get up higher in the trees.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sadists who torture, and those who command them</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2006/10/05/sadists-who-torture-and-those-who-command-them/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Oct 2006 00:14:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2006/10/05/sadists-who-torture-and-those-who-command-them/</guid>
      <description>Fred Clark has a provocative article, Dirty work, that makes an interesting point about people who do the ‘dirty work’ of torture, such as our American agents who engage in tortuous activities such as waterboarding. First, he notes that these people, at the end of the day, must enjoy their work, and thus are worthy of being called sadists, sociopaths, sexual perverts or worse. (This reminds me of Miss Hardcastle in Lewis’s That Hideous Strength).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Powerset reveal</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2006/10/05/a-powerset-reveal/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2006 11:36:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2006/10/05/a-powerset-reveal/</guid>
      <description>An article in Ventureblog about Powerset, the company I work for, has kicked up a minor storm in the blogosphere about Powerset and the very idea of natural language search. I’d just like to point people to a weblog post by Barney Pell, our CEO, on Powerset and Natural Language Search. For those who might wonder why I’m working for Powerset, Barney’s vision explains it well:
 Seen in this light, there is enormous room for fundamental innovation in search, as the game has only just begun.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AARP card arrives…</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2006/10/03/aarp-card-arrives/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2006 19:26:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2006/10/03/aarp-card-arrives/</guid>
      <description>OK, so we decided to join AARP…it’s cheap, and has some good benefits. Our cards arrived today, and I’m a little worried. It says, “Expiration: Sep 2009.”</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rachel Miller Jacobs</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2006/08/21/rachel-miller-jacobs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2006 11:08:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2006/08/21/rachel-miller-jacobs/</guid>
      <description>Rachel Miller Jacobs, of Kern Street Mennonite Church in South Bend, Indiana, was ordained yesterday. Rachel is one of the Goshen, Indiana Sacred Harp singers, and it was with great pleasure that some of us were able to sing as a prelude to her ordination service, which was marked by good prayers, lovely singing, an excellent call to ministry by one of her seminary professors, and much obvious love for Rachel by the congregration she serves as the minister of spiritual formation, and by Rachel for the people she serves and from whom she has learned.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Watermelon toothpaste</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2006/08/11/watermelon-toothpaste/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Aug 2006 15:04:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2006/08/11/watermelon-toothpaste/</guid>
      <description>A confession: my wife bought some watermelon-flavored toothpaste for our daughter. She didn’t like it particularly, but I did. It’s a very strange translucent green, and it’s quite sweet; I suspect it’s the sweetness, not the strange color that I like.
When I was thinking about moving to San Francisco to work for the startup, I began to suspect that the toothpaste would run out about the same time as when I might come to the Bay Area.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>At 50, everyone has the face they deserve</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2006/07/28/at-50-everyone-has-the-face-they-deserve/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2006 05:12:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2006/07/28/at-50-everyone-has-the-face-they-deserve/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Several things of note</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2006/07/21/several-things-of-note/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2006 04:09:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2006/07/21/several-things-of-note/</guid>
      <description>I work up so joyful this morning; it is so nice to have Bess and Jane with me here in San Francisco for a while. People at the Church of the Sojourners, and in particular the members who live in the Potrero houses where I live have been so kind: Naomi welcomed Jane and Bess with hand-made signs, and Louise made marvelous boquets for our bedrooms and a box of “movie treats” for Jane.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Firbys across America</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2006/07/16/firbys-across-america/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2006 04:06:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2006/07/16/firbys-across-america/</guid>
      <description>Jim Firby is blogging his family’s trip from Chicago to California, visiting sights (Carhenge!) and sites (they collect National Park passport stamps) along the way. The trip starts here. Insert obligatory, “my how the girls have grown” here. While humming “California, here I come!“</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two Poems for depressives by Chesterton</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2006/07/02/two-poems-for-depressives-by-chesterton/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jul 2006 17:50:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2006/07/02/two-poems-for-depressives-by-chesterton/</guid>
      <description>Evening
 Here dies another day During which I have had eyes, ears, hands And the great world round me; And with tomorrow begins another Why am I allowed two? (quoted in Philip Yancey’s book, Soul Survivor; mentioned to me by Bess).
 A Prayer in Darkness
 This much, O heaven–if I should brood or rave, Pity me not; but let the world be fed, Yea, in my madness if I strike me dead, Heed you the grass that grows upon my grave.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Remembering Joanie Hahn</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2006/06/21/remembering-joanie-hahn/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2006 03:42:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2006/06/21/remembering-joanie-hahn/</guid>
      <description>Sad news:
 Hahn, Joan T. Age 52, June 20, 2006. Beloved wife of Edward J. Hahn. Loving mother of Erica (Peter Treiber) Fitzgerald, Jeffrey (Jami) Fitzgerald, Steven Fitzgerald and step-children, Brendan (Catherine) Hahn and Alicia (Michael) Farris. Proud grandmother of Camden, Jordan, Shane, Ethan, Benjamin, Jacob and Justin. Dear sister of Virginia Hermann, Louise “Nickie” (Keith) Greenfield and Edwin (Paula) Snay. Mrs. Hahn devoted her life to serving Jesus and others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>O Happy Day</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2006/06/11/o-happy-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jun 2006 20:32:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2006/06/11/o-happy-day/</guid>
      <description>Our daughter Janine was baptized this morning by the Kalamazoo River at Historic Bridge Park near Battle Creek, Michigan, presided over by Pastor Tom Schwartz and Elder Eldon Christophel. This is a (rare!) family picture of us all together: Will, Bess and Mark Fitzgerald, Janine Fitzgerald in front. She was baptized along with eight other youth from our church. Leanell Schwartz taught the baptism preparation class.
_O happy day, that fixed my choice On Thee, my Savior and my God!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New camera; home for the weekend</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2006/06/09/new-camera-home-for-the-weekend/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jun 2006 00:58:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2006/06/09/new-camera-home-for-the-weekend/</guid>
      <description>[ ]1 Bess bought me a new, light camera for Father’s Day; we hope to use it for daughter Jane’s baptism on Sunday. This is one of the first pictures I’ve taken with it. It’s nice to be in Michigan, if only for the weekend.
Addendum: I wrote the following additional verse to Foreign Lander for Bess:
I’ve been to California, Our fortune for to seek, I sit among the mighty, Though I am mighty meek.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lorenzo’s ride</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2006/06/04/lorenzos-ride/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2006 06:08:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2006/06/04/lorenzos-ride/</guid>
      <description>My co-worker Lorenzo is starting out on his SF to LA AIDS LifeCycle bike trip, and is keeping a weblog as he rides (posting from his cell phone). Safe home, Lorenzo!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eiffel Tower and Polish Pilgrim</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2006/05/29/eiffel-tower-and-polish-pilgrim/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2006 23:29:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2006/05/29/eiffel-tower-and-polish-pilgrim/</guid>
      <description>I went to the top of the Eiffel Tower today. It was pretty crowded, but well worth the wait for the view of Paris. But the coolest thing in my opinion was the apartment the M. Eiffel had at the top. I think I read about this before, but they’ve placed effigies of Eiffel and his daughter Claire entertaining–get this–Thomas Edison, who, in the English translation, is listed as an ‘American physician and inventor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RIP, Liz Purchase</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2006/05/24/rip-liz-purchase/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 May 2006 07:27:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2006/05/24/rip-liz-purchase/</guid>
      <description>Dear Liz,
How we loved you. You were such an example to us when you started the “Bread Box,” a local restaurant and meeting place, to provide nutritious, home-made food inexpensively. And you did it when you were in your late 60’s–as part of your “outward journey” to serve God in the world, which also included your leadership in the local Bread for the World group.
When Yofi, our beloved cat, scratched our new baby’s face out of jealousy, and we had to find it a home, you took Yofi in, and made her fat and happy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leo in motion</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2006/05/20/leo-in-motion/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 May 2006 02:16:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2006/05/20/leo-in-motion/</guid>
      <description>Here’s a picture of Leo, who lives downstairs. He’s real fast, so it’s hard to catch a picture of him:
He tried to teach me to smile, but I don’t think I’ll ever smile as big as he does.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to die well</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2006/05/15/how-to-die-well/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2006 04:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2006/05/15/how-to-die-well/</guid>
      <description>We attended the memorial service for Esther Chistophel this weekend. What a lovely service, and we learned a bit more about her last days and hours. She went to a hospice, where family and friends were welcomed. She was attended by most of her extended family. On her last day, several family members came to sing at various times. So did our pastor’s wife, Leanell, whom Esther love to hear sing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ruth Christophel and Esther Christophel</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2006/05/13/ruth-christophel-and-esther-christophel/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 May 2006 04:16:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2006/05/13/ruth-christophel-and-esther-christophel/</guid>
      <description>I want to record the passing of two dear friends.
Ruth Christophel was a very dear woman, the oldest and sweetest person in our small Mennonite church, the wife of the founding pastor. She lived a long full life, and desired to go home to be with Jesus.
Esther Chistophel was a good friend to many, including Bess and me: we almost always sought her out for a word or two at church services, because she was so kind and loving and interested in the world around her.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beauty and ugliness at the Golden Gate</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2006/05/05/beauty-and-ugliness-at-the-golden-gate/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2006 05:33:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2006/05/05/beauty-and-ugliness-at-the-golden-gate/</guid>
      <description>San Francisco has always been a favorite city. It has so much beauty, both natural and man-made, and the natural and the man-made coexist so well. The great symbol of this is, of course, the Golden Gate bridge, its beautiful symmetry linking the city to the glories of Marin County, rising above the bay, perhaps enveloped by clouds.
This is the first time I’ve lived in the city, though, and I think what has struck me most has been the people–there are lots of ’em, and many different kinds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mid-week updates</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2006/04/26/mid-week-updates/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2006 04:31:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2006/04/26/mid-week-updates/</guid>
      <description>Here are some mid-week updates, in case you care:
 It looks like I have a place to stay until fall (at least): the Church of the Sojourners is planning to let me stay as a guest member. This makes me very happy. I had great fun singing at the 2nd Annual Golden Gate Sacred Harp Convention this past weekend. I even met someone who already knew by because of things I post to the Internet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Changes</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2006/04/20/changes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2006 01:01:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2006/04/20/changes/</guid>
      <description>Tomorrow I leave for California–here’s the plan: I have one more week to work at NASA, and then, on May 1, I start at Powerset, a new search company. Exciting, and a bit scary: the plan is for me to be in California (say) three weeks per month and (say) one week in Michigan. Bess is on board with this, but we’re all a bit daunted at being apart so much.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Family story</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2006/03/21/family-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2006 02:28:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2006/03/21/family-story/</guid>
      <description>Brother Steve just called, and we talked about Scrabble, and my post about playing sorbetto. He reminded me that my Great Uncle Kennard and my Grandma used to play Scrabble every day until they got into an argument over whether “obit” was a legitimate play. They never played again.
According to the online Scrabble dictionary, “obit” is just fine. Grandma was right.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stinky buts</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2006/03/16/stinky-buts/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2006 03:26:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2006/03/16/stinky-buts/</guid>
      <description>We had parent-teacher conferences today. This is almost always a discouraging time.
Jane’s teacher showed us a “persuasive essay” she wrote for her social studies class. The students were to take a stand of whether the US government should spy on people to prevent terrorism. Jane’s first sentence went something like this:
The US government should spy on people to prevent terrorism, but they should do so in a way the protects the privacy rights of citizens.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lover of the Lord</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2006/03/16/lover-of-the-lord/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2006 13:41:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2006/03/16/lover-of-the-lord/</guid>
      <description>Earlier this month, the annual Pauline Creel Birthday singing was held in Wayne , Michigan (in the Ann Arbor/Detroit area). “Miss Pauline” comes from one of the “singing families” in the Sacred Harp tradition–that is, one of the extended families in the South that kept (and continue to keep) Sacred Harp music alive. Many of her family come up north for her birthday singing–I think I heard that some 30 people came for her 91st birthday.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spring seems to be arriving</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2006/03/12/spring-seems-to-be-arriving/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2006 01:26:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2006/03/12/spring-seems-to-be-arriving/</guid>
      <description>Spring seems to be arriving. We drove across southern Michigan yesterday (to pick son Mark up from a weeklong internship with my Aunt Kathleen, who is a real estate agent), and then to mid-Michigan to take Mark back to university. We saw dozens of groupings of Canada geese arriving, as well as sand hill cranes. Three fat turkeys were waddling in one field, and lots of hawks. One gave me a good show as it came in across the highway to attack its prey on the center strip.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A psalm for Tom Fox</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2006/03/11/a-psalm-for-tom-fox/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Mar 2006 23:15:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2006/03/11/a-psalm-for-tom-fox/</guid>
      <description>The Light is before me, and in me, and surrounds me. The Light soothes my fears and eases my tremblings. I waited before the powerful. I sought to stand in the way of great oppression, Aware that brutality desires hidden corners and not Light.
Lesser oppressors came and surrounded me as well. Surrounded my friends, and me. Yet I held out the Light, even as they hid us, And pursued justice in places of fear and anger.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Levees</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2006/03/02/levees/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2006 21:59:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2006/03/02/levees/</guid>
      <description>Bush (four days after Hurricane Katrina hit): “I don’t think anybody anticipated the breach of the levees.”
Max Mayfield, Director of the National Hurricane Center (19 hours before Katrina lands): “I don’t think anyone can tell you with any confidence right now whether the levees will be topped or not, but that’s obviously a very, very grave concern.”
See AP video converage of Bush’s briefing by FEMA before the landfall (Quicktime movie).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2006/02/28/no/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2006 20:58:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2006/02/28/no/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Happy Birthday, Dad!</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2006/02/26/happy-birthday-dad/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Feb 2006 16:01:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2006/02/26/happy-birthday-dad/</guid>
      <description>My father celebrates his 75th birthday on Monday, February 27. Three of my four brothers were able to come to a party to help him celebrate: from left to right: Ed, Dave, Dan, me; Dad (Harold) in the center. Steve attended virtually. Kudos to his nursing home, Tendercare of Westwood , for helping make this happen. (Also there: Dan’s wife Lynn, Dave’s wife Joanie, Ed’s wife Amy and son Davie, Bess, Mark and Jane.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ceci n’est pas un card</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2006/02/13/ceci-nest-pas-un-card/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2006 22:01:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2006/02/13/ceci-nest-pas-un-card/</guid>
      <description>Happy Valentine’s Day, Bess</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No teenagers in our household</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2006/01/04/no-teenagers-in-our-household/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2006 17:45:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2006/01/04/no-teenagers-in-our-household/</guid>
      <description>For exactly one day, there are no teenagers in our household. Mark turned 20 today, and Jane turns 13 tomorrow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Harmonia Sacra</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2006/01/02/harmonia-sacra/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2006 13:10:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2006/01/02/harmonia-sacra/</guid>
      <description>Again this year I was able to participate in the New Year’s Day Harmonia Sacra singing in Elkhart (Indiana), ably led by James Gingerich and Matthew Lind. I’ve learned a lot in the last year, and so I think it was all the more enjoyable and pleasant to be there. In December, I sang with the Goshen Sacred Harp group, which traditionally sings out of the Harmonia Sacra for the second half of their December singing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Searches</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2005/12/20/searches/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2005 18:59:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2005/12/20/searches/</guid>
      <description>According to Google’s search history counts, I’ve done 30 searches per day (on average) since September 7. Yikes! That doesn’t even count Yahoo searches.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Joyce Park, alpha geek</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2005/11/24/joyce-park-alpha-geek/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Nov 2005 03:11:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2005/11/24/joyce-park-alpha-geek/</guid>
      <description>O’Reilly is running a series on how alpha geeks got into programming; my friend Joyce Park is number 2 in the series. I knew Joyce back when she was just a beta geek 🙂</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The day is past and gone</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2005/10/17/the-day-is-past-and-gone/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2005 12:55:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2005/10/17/the-day-is-past-and-gone/</guid>
      <description>Really good Kalamazoo Sacred Harp singing yesterday. There were only six people when we began to sing, but with Roger Williams singing bass, Molly Williams on alto, and Ann Miczulski singing treble, and the always strong leading tenor of Samuel Sommers, we were well covered. We started with lots of minor plain tunes–Mear, Wells and the like. We sang Stafford, the object of some controversy because of its words, because some of us didn’t even know how it sounded (with some instructions on how to change the words, and explicit permission not to sing).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Doing the Martin Shuffle</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2005/10/10/doing-the-martin-shuffle/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2005 14:52:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2005/10/10/doing-the-martin-shuffle/</guid>
      <description>Fun Peter Norvig post on using randomized techniques to listen to a particular song on an iPod shuffle: Doing the Martin Shuffle (with your iPod). The ‘Martin’ of the ‘Martin Shuffle’ is Charles Martin. Charles was the 2nd grad student of Chris Riesbeck‘s to graduate; I was the 3rd. We both did NLP research, and Charles was my boss for two days (if I remember correctly) when I joined “Intell/Agent Systems,” which now seems like a long time ago.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emil’s</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2005/10/03/emils/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2005 06:11:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2005/10/03/emils/</guid>
      <description>Bess and I discovered–somewhat by accident–the Italian restaurant where we had our first date 28 years ago or so: Emil’s, in Lansing, Michigan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Great Menno Fun</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2005/09/26/great-fun/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2005 13:09:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2005/09/26/great-fun/</guid>
      <description>We had great fun at the Michiana Mennonite Relief Sale; Bess even bought two baby quilts at auction. I like the Necker Cubist quality of this one she bought.
I especially enjoyed hearing and singing “Dedication Anthem,” by Lowell Mason, often called “606” by Mennonites because that was the page number in the (1969) Mennonite Hymnal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>lemonodor</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2005/09/23/lemonodor/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2005 17:35:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2005/09/23/lemonodor/</guid>
      <description>Great picture of John Wiseman aka lemondor by Adam Rifkin (shown me by Joyce).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Michiana Mennonite Relief Sale</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2005/09/23/michiana-mennonite-relief-sale/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2005 12:33:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2005/09/23/michiana-mennonite-relief-sale/</guid>
      <description>We’re heading down for the 2005 Michiana Mennonite Relief Sale tomorrow (and maybe tonight). This Quicktime video does a pretty good job at capturing what one usually sees. Bess loves the quilt auction; up until this year, I’ve usually ridden round and round with one or both kids on the horse-drawn wagon, but the kids are not so little any more…</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>i thank You God</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2005/09/19/i-thank-you-god/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2005 05:09:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2005/09/19/i-thank-you-god/</guid>
      <description>Today was a good, happy day:
 Driving to church today, Jane (our daughter) had us laughing out loud with her jokes and wordplay. I led worship at church today, and people affirmed that leadership, even though a lot of it has been leading singing a cappella. It looks like I’ll be heading up the ‘worship team’ at church, and like many beginnings, I’m happy thinking about the possibilities of positive change.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Zoo!</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2005/09/05/the-zoo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2005 00:26:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2005/09/05/the-zoo/</guid>
      <description>We made a quick trip to Binder Park Zoo today–a local zoo with a really great ‘Africa Safari’ open air exhibit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>those which, from a distance, look like flies (*)</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2005/08/17/those-which-from-a-distance-look-like-flies/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2005 02:14:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2005/08/17/those-which-from-a-distance-look-like-flies/</guid>
      <description>Daughter Jane straightened out our DVDs today, at her mother’s request. She decided to organize by genre:
 Fighting movies (e.g. Crouching Tiger, Hidden Dragon), Animation (e.g. The Incredibles), Classicish (e.g. It’s a Wonderful Life), Magic (e.g., Harry Potter), Modern Action (e.g., Charlie’s Angels), Princess Movies (e.g. The Princess Diaries), Movies That I Have No Intention of Watching in the Next Millenium (e.g. 2001, A Space Oddesey).  (*) See The Analytical Language of John Wilkins.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ratios and percentages</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2005/01/15/ratios-and-percentages/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jan 2005 22:36:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2005/01/15/ratios-and-percentages/</guid>
      <description>Daughter Jane is taking the SAT test next week as part of a program to foster academically talented junior high students. We’re fairly confident of her language skills (today she asked me what ‘subcutaneous meant), but she’s fairly math adverse, so Bess asked me to tutor her a little. It’s hard to know how to prepare a 12 year old for the math section of the SATs, but today we spent about an hour discussing odds and percentages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More Michigania</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2005/01/08/more-michigania/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jan 2005 08:33:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2005/01/08/more-michigania/</guid>
      <description>I came across a You know you’re from Michigan when… list, and it had the following item:
 When giving directions, you refer to “A Michigan Left.”Hmm, I’ve never heard of this, but searching the web I found this: The Michigan Left-Hand Turn, complete with diagrams. Fortunately, we don’t have any of these in Kalamazoo, although they’re a bane whenever I drive Gratiot Avenue when I visit my father near Detroit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Happy New Year</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2005/01/01/happy-new-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 17:36:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2005/01/01/happy-new-year/</guid>
      <description>We spent New Year’s Eve the way we usually do–with a group of friends we’ve been celebrating with every year for more than two decades–the Aldermans, the Neevils, and the Robbins (participating via instant messaging from Honduras), plus Bess’s sister Jean and her two boys. Mark was off to a ‘black-tie’ party of this own (having found a spiffy tuxedo for $20 dollars–shades of Napoleon Dynamite–at a thrift store).
We played our usual guys vs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Christmas letter</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2004/12/09/christmas-letter/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Dec 2004 22:53:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2004/12/09/christmas-letter/</guid>
      <description>Our 2004 (and 2003!) Christmas newsletter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Christmas addresses</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2004/12/08/christmas-addresses/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Dec 2004 08:56:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2004/12/08/christmas-addresses/</guid>
      <description>Every year I attempt to update our address list, especially in order to send out Christmas cards. The original database of addresses I created is gone; I can’t remember what I originally used. Last year was too choatic to do anything. This year I decided to create the list from scratch. In fact, I decided I would just write out addresses in an address book.
In the end, though, I had a brainstorm.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
