<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Whim on Will&#39;s Whims</title>
    <link>http://example.org/categories/whim/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Whim on Will&#39;s Whims</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2014 19:58:02 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://example.org/categories/whim/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Nobel Prize of X</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2014/08/11/nobel-prize/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2014 19:58:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2014/08/11/nobel-prize/</guid>
      <description>Awards that are “the Nobel Prize of” that field:
 Math: The Fields Medal Computer Science: The A.M. Turing Award Food: The World Food Prize Water: The Stockholm Water Prize Education: The Harold W. McGraw, Jr. Prize in Education Manufacturing: Shingo Prize for Excellence in Manufacturing Geography: Le Lauréat Prix International de Géographie Vautrin Lud Architecture: Pritzker Prize Gastronomy: White Guide Global Gastronomy Award Environmentalism: The Goldman Prize Music: The Polar Music Prize  Well, that’s enough for one day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>There is more than one way to skin a tab</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2014/06/05/one-way-skin-tab/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2014 00:37:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2014/06/05/one-way-skin-tab/</guid>
      <description>The tab is always the last to know · There is more than one way to skin a tab · Fish and guests smell after three tabs · Judge not, that thy tab be not judged. · Physician, heal thy tab · Pride goes before a tab · Cold hands, warm tab · No one can make you feel inferior without your tab · Never let the sun go down on your tab · The apple never falls far from the tab · Never put off until tomorrow what you can do tab · In for a penny, in for a tab · If you think that you know everything, then you’re a Jack tab · A tab saved is a tab earned · Faint heart never won fair tab (Scott), · Better safe than tab · A rising tide lifts all tabs · Barking tabs seldom bite · Good talk saves the tab · If you have never seen the bottom of the tab, you cannot know how tall it stands · Two wrongs do not make a tab · Every little bit tabs · An Englishman’s home is his tab · Laugh before breakfast, cry before tab.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Year’s Rap</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2013/01/03/new-years-rap/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2013 20:35:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2013/01/03/new-years-rap/</guid>
      <description>(all the words ending in “EY1 SH AH0 N Z” from the CMU pronouncing dictionary)
Impatiens, Revelations, abbreviations, aberrations, accommodations, accreditations, accumulations, accusations, adaptations, administration’s, administrations, administrations’, admirations, affiliations, affirmations, allegations, allocations, alterations, altercations, amplifications, amputations, animations, annotations, anticipations, appalachians, appellations, applications, appropriations, approximations, arbitrations, aspirations, assassinations, association’s, associations, authentications, authorizations, aviation’s, aviations, calculations, cancellations, capitalizations, carnations, castrations, celebrations, certifications, characterizations, circulations, citations, civilizations, clarifications, classifications, collaborations, combinations, commemorations, communication’s, communications, communications’, compensations, compilations, complications, computations, concentrations, condemnations, configurations, confirmations, confrontations, congratulations, congregation’s, congregations, conjugations, connotations, consecrations, considerations, consolations, consolidations, constellation’s, constellations, consultations, conversations, cooperations, corporation’s, corporations, corporations’, corps, correlations, creations, croatian’s, croatians, croatians’, crustaceans, dalmatians, decapitations, declarations, decorations, degradations, delegation’s, delegations, deliberations, demarcations, demonstrations, denationalizations, denomination’s, denominations, denunciations, deportations, depreciations, depredations, deprivations, desecrations, designations, destinations, determination’s, determinations, detonations, devaluations, deviations, discolorations, dislocations, diversifications, donations, dramatizations, duplications, durations, education’s, educations, elevations, eliminations, emanations, emancipations, emigrations, estimations, evacuations, evaluations, exacerbations, exaggerations, examinations, excavations, exclamations, exhortations, expectations, expirations, explanations, exploration’s, explorations, expropriations, fabrications, federation’s, federations, flirtations, fluctuations, formations, formulations, fortifications, foundation’s, foundations, frustrations, generalizations, generation’s, generations, gradations, graduations, gyrations, haitians, haitiens, hallucinations, hesitations, hospitalizations, humiliations, identifications, illustrations, imaginations, imitations, immunizations, implications, improvisations, inaugurations, incarnations, inclinations, incorporation’s, incorporations, indications, infestations, inflation’s, inflations, information’s, informations, innovations, inoculations, insinuations, inspirations, installations, integrations, interpretations, interrogations, intimations, intonations, inundations, investigations, invitations, irritations, justifications, lacerations, legislation’s, legislations, liberalizations, limitations, liquidations, litigations, locations, machinations, magnifications, malformations, manifestations, manipulations, medications, meditations, migrations, ministrations, miscalculations, mischaracterizations, miscreations, misrepresentations, mobilizations, modifications, motivations, mutations, mutilations, nation’s, nationalizations, nations, nations’, negotiations, nominations, notations, notifications, obligations, observations, occupations, operations, orations, orchestrations, organisations, organization’s, organizations, orientations, originations, oscillations, ovations, ovulations, palpitations, participations, patients, perforations, permutations, perturbations, plantations, pontifications, populations, preoccupations, preparations, presentations, privations, privatizations, proclamations, prognostications, pronunciations, protestations, provocations, publication’s, publications, publications’, qualifications, quotations, radiation’s, radiations, ramifications, ration, realizations, recapitalizations, recitations, recommendations, reconciliations, recriminations, registrations, regulations, rehabilitations, relations, relocations, renegotiations, reorganizations, reparations, representations, reputations, reservations, resignations, restorations, revaluations, reverberations, revocations, rotations, ruminations, sensations, separations, simulations, situation’s, situations, solicitations, specifications, speculations, station, sterilizations, stipulations, strangulations, subluxations, summations, syndications, tabulations, telecommunications, telecommunications’, temptations, terminations, transformations, translations, transportation’s, transportations, tribulations, ulcerations, vacation, vaccinations, valuations, variations, vibrations, violations, visitations, vocations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Non-Chaos, or English Spelling Defended in Rhyme</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2012/01/13/the-non-chaos-or-english-spelling-defended-in-rhyme/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2012 05:01:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2012/01/13/the-non-chaos-or-english-spelling-defended-in-rhyme/</guid>
      <description>Dearest creature in creation, Study English pronunciation. It’s more regular in its core Than pundits, who focus on its more Erratic ways, would have you believe. Perhaps they simply cannot conceive Of any system not based in Latin— They would choose, I suppose, to flatten All writing to “one form, one sound” But, really, regularities abound. Consider, how we pronounce the plural Form of words; Imagine the neural Work of reading “dogs” and “cats.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Things that are stentorian</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2010/12/05/things-that-are-stentorian/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Dec 2010 02:47:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2010/12/05/things-that-are-stentorian/</guid>
      <description>The first twenty five things that are stentorian, according to the examples at Wordnik:
 tones [xxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxx] voices [xxxxxxxxxxxxxxx] commands [xxx] defenses [xx] styles [xx] rings  growls  moments  ways  jocks  phrases  resonances  screams  baritones  announcements  greetings  pronouncements  engines  insults  thickness  yelps  breathing  wheezing  barks  snores   “Stentorian” derives from Stentor, a herald of the Greeks during the Trojan War.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quomodocunquizing clusterfists</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2010/11/29/quonwdocuncluizing-clusterfists/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Nov 2010 12:13:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2010/11/29/quonwdocuncluizing-clusterfists/</guid>
      <description>Now, here’s an insult:
“Another thing there is,” he says, ” that fixeth a grievous scandal upon that nation in matter of philargyrie, or love of money, and it is this: There hath been in London, and repairing to it, for these many years together, a knot of Scotish bankers, collybists, or coine-coursers, of traffickers in merchandise to and againe, and of men of other professions, who by hook and crook, las et nefas, slight and might, (all being as fish their net could catch), having feathered their nests to some purpose, look so idolatrously upon their Dagon of wealth, and so closely, (like the earth’s dull center), hug all unto themselves, that for no respect of vertue, honour, kindred, patriotism, or whatever else, (be it never so recommendable), will they depart from so much as one single peny, whose emission doth not, without any hazard of loss, in a very short time superlucrate beyond all conscience an additionall increase to the heap of that stock which they so much adore; which churlish and tenacious humor hath made many that were not acquainted with any else of that country, to imagine all their compatriots infected with the same leprosie of a wretched peevishness, whereof those quomodocunquizing clusterfists and rapacious varlets have given of late such cannibal-like proofs, by their inhumanity and obdurate carriage towards some, (whose shoe-strings they are not worthy to unty), that were it not that a more able pen then [than] mine will assuredly not faile to jerk them on all sides, in case, by their better demeanour for the future, they endeavour not to wipe off the blot wherewith their native country, by their sordid avarice and miserable baseness, hath been so foully stained, I would at this very instant blaze them out in their names and surnames, notwithstanding tbe vizard of Presbyterian zeal wherewith they maske themselves, that like so many wolves, foxes, or Athenian Timons, they might in all times coming be debarred the benefit of any honest conversation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>World’s longest logogol</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2010/11/01/worlds-longest-logogol/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2010 17:01:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2010/11/01/worlds-longest-logogol/</guid>
      <description>It was fun to review the world’s longest logogol (or palindrome) on Peter Norvig’s website today. A logogol is a word or phrase that has the same letters going forwards or going backwards. I think it’s cool that “logogol” is itself a logogol.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clichés used in an Oxford Dictionary anti-clichés article</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2010/10/15/cliches-used-in-an-oxford-dictionary-anti-cliches-article/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Oct 2010 14:27:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2010/10/15/cliches-used-in-an-oxford-dictionary-anti-cliches-article/</guid>
      <description>We all hate clichés. As this article on avoiding clichés from the Oxford Dictionaries says, they’re not always possible to avoid.
Here are some clichés used in the article’s text. These are not examples they give, but clichés they use in the body text:
 Once you’ve spotted a cliché… they’ve lost their impact [they’ve] become stale Some people just tune out make a point [they may miss the point that you’re trying to make] use [something] as a starting point indispensable advice  At least they didn’t say “avoid clichés like the plague,” the clichéd anti-cliché joke.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Center embedding in the wild (sort of)</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2010/10/14/center-embedding-in-the-wild-sort-of/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Oct 2010 02:25:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2010/10/14/center-embedding-in-the-wild-sort-of/</guid>
      <description>Around 9:10 minutes into Community, Season 2, Episode 3, “The Psychology of Letting Go“.
Annie: Bitter much?
Britta: Say “Bitter much” much?
Annie: Say “Say ‘Bitter much’ much?&amp;rsquo;” much?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Obscene intensification of adjectives (a bit NSFW)</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2010/09/30/obscene-intensification-of-adjectives-a-bit-nsfw/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2010 05:25:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2010/09/30/obscene-intensification-of-adjectives-a-bit-nsfw/</guid>
      <description>XKCD, a ‘webcomic of romance, sarcasm, math, and language’, presents a hand-drawn chart of the frequency with which ‘fucking adjective‘ or ‘adjective as shit’ can be found in web search results.
Well, with the Bing Ngram data, we can provide more exact figures which don’t depend on all of the choice and ranking decisions made by a search engine to include or not a page in a result, and (in particular) the estimate of the number of pages on which the term appears.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First mention: “Clean and sober”</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2010/08/09/first-mention-clean-and-sober/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2010 17:20:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2010/08/09/first-mention-clean-and-sober/</guid>
      <description>In one of the “Mad Men” discussions, someone asks if it was anachronistic to describe Freddy Rumsen as “clean and sober” in 1963 (from here, I think.)
The first clear use of this expression in the New York Times archives is from August 28, 1892, which has the embedded note in an article about a murder trial:
 DEAR MISS CLOVER: WIll you meet me outside the Canterbury at 7:30 to-night?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alumin(i)um</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2010/08/09/aluminium/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2010 17:07:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2010/08/09/aluminium/</guid>
      <description>I enjoyed reading the Wikipedia page about its “lamest edit wars.” One of these edit wars was whether the article on what Americans call “aluminum” and what Brits call “aluminium” should have, as its fundamental title, “Aluminum,” or “Aluminium.” And, one of the arguments presented in favo(u)r of “Aluminum” was that more Google hits are available for the US spelling than the UK spelling. “Ghits” is notoriously unreliable (as are Bing hits and the other search engines), since the number of search results reported are subject to lots of factors, not of which is tied directly to actual number of documents returned.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hal Eisen</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2009/11/04/hal-eisen/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Nov 2009 17:52:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2009/11/04/hal-eisen/</guid>
      <description>Hal Eisen sail’d to the horizon. He’d rather suffer beri-beri than write code that’s proprietary.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Third person singular human</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2009/06/23/third-person-singular-human/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2009 12:57:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2009/06/23/third-person-singular-human/</guid>
      <description>It has often been noted that English is deficient because it lacks a third-person pronoun that can refer to any person, without respect to sexual gender. Although some claim that “he” can refer to anyone in sentences like (1), most linguists agree that maleness is much more salient in these cases than a generic sense.
(1) Everyone should do his own work.
There are at least six common solutions proposed:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Things you can get down in …</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2009/03/19/things-you-can-get-down-in/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2009 20:23:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2009/03/19/things-you-can-get-down-in/</guid>
      <description>get down in the dumps get down in the mud get down in the dirt get down in the trenches get down in the gutter get down in the muck get down in the cornfields get down in the weeds get down in the wheat  I saw the expression “get down in the wheat” for the first time today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Epoch success</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2009/02/13/epoch-success/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2009 23:36:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2009/02/13/epoch-success/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Epoch odometer</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2009/02/12/epoch-odometer/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2009 05:42:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2009/02/12/epoch-odometer/</guid>
      <description>My epoch odometer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The gospel bin</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2008/08/25/the-gospel-bin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2008 12:53:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2008/08/25/the-gospel-bin/</guid>
      <description>[Amazon.com] MP3 Albums &amp;gt; Christian &amp;amp; Gospel &amp;gt; Country Gospel &amp;gt; Sort Low to High
 God’s Gonna Ride a Harley Golden Bowls of Compassion Radiant Redbird When Santa Claus Met Jesus Pale Rider Time is a Space Mama was Judged Tha Chronicles of Junglistic Hip Hop (EP) Jesus Is My Spotter – the Race Car Driver’s Anthem Orca Chantress Beluga Shaman  No customer reviews yet. Be the first!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who knew? Balloons in the movies</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2008/08/14/who-knew-balloons-in-the-movies/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2008 15:20:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2008/08/14/who-knew-balloons-in-the-movies/</guid>
      <description>I had no idea balloons played such a role in the movies: see VSL.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>100 most common English words</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2008/08/06/100-most-common-english-words/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2008 19:58:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2008/08/06/100-most-common-english-words/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;First, take &lt;a href=&#34;http://codebox.no-ip.net/controller?page=misc.QuizCommonWords&#34;&gt;this fun quiz&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then …&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mark’d</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2008/06/28/markd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jun 2008 00:38:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2008/06/28/markd/</guid>
      <description>A response to Mark‘s tagging me.
Seven factz about me:
 Will Fitzgerald didn’t use a computer until he was 23. It had cards. It is difficult for Will Fitzgerald to refer to himself in the third person. Despite his descriptivist linguistic training, Will Fitzgerald tries to distinguish ‘between’ and ‘among’. Will Fitzgerald was known as “Bill” until he was 33. Will Fitzgerald has half of a house named in his honor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Book of Psalms</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2008/06/16/the-book-of-psalms/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2008 00:50:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2008/06/16/the-book-of-psalms/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The evolution of a Ruby programmer</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2008/06/05/the-evolution-of-a-ruby-programmer/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jun 2008 12:58:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2008/06/05/the-evolution-of-a-ruby-programmer/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How do you spell X? Y.</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2008/06/03/how-do-you-spell-x-y/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2008 04:47:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2008/06/03/how-do-you-spell-x-y/</guid>
      <description>Many of us are familiar with the commercial in which the question is asked, “How do you spell ‘relief’?” And the answer is “R-O-L-A-I-D-S.” According to Wikipedia, this commercial has been around since the 1970’s.
I came across an earlier example from 1793, in Elder John Leland’s “The history of Jack Nips”:
 Like other boys, I wished to be in fashion, and as the Presbyterians were the most fashionable, I applied myself to the study of their books, but was not a little puzzled to reconcile their writings with my boyish thoughts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Willie Mays: Don’t touch blasting caps</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2008/04/13/willie-mays-dont-touch-blasting-caps/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Apr 2008 11:58:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2008/04/13/willie-mays-dont-touch-blasting-caps/</guid>
      <description>This Willie Mays PSA really scared me as a kid.
 You protect your arms and hands legs and save your eyes. If you see a blasting cap remember now, don’t touch them. Tell a police or a fireman or whatever it is. Have fun like I do with those (baseball mitt, bat and ball) and not with these (blasting caps!!) Anyone I’ve ever met who is exactly my age in years and grew up near Detroit remembers this with fear.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Foul shots</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2008/04/05/foul-shots/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Apr 2008 16:05:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2008/04/05/foul-shots/</guid>
      <description>I talked to my brother Dave on the phone today, and we agreed that we haven’t played basketball in 300 years. But we have a hoop in the backyard, and I’ve decided to try to get ‘good’ at shooting foul shots. The advantage of foul shots, of course, is that you don’t have to move very much.
My first try was abysmal: 11/50. Yesterday was worse: 10/50. Today, almost, but not quite, not terrible: 19/50.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Powerstache!</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2008/04/05/powerstache/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Apr 2008 15:54:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2008/04/05/powerstache/</guid>
      <description>My co-minions at Powerset have been growing (or faking growing) facial hair in the run up to our beta launch. And, of course, it has its own blog: Powerstache.com. It’s even made the LA Times, and Michael Arrington’s initial take on our beta product even mentions it.
Chris pretty much wins, though.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>expression of the day: ‘go off piste’</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2008/03/19/expression-of-the-day-go-off-piste/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2008 15:32:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2008/03/19/expression-of-the-day-go-off-piste/</guid>
      <description>From ‘In pursuit of the G-d shot‘:
 Millions of people probably get great coffee every morning with a standard home machine and ground coffee from a supermarket. I was starting to worry that, with a process that has as many variables as pulling an espresso, once you’re daft enough to go off piste, things get monumentally messy in a way only explicable with chaos theory. To go off piste is to go off the trail (in cross-country skiing, for example), to do something non-standard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fum, fum, fum!</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2008/01/07/fum-fum-fum/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jan 2008 17:34:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2008/01/07/fum-fum-fum/</guid>
      <description>Here is my translation of the Catalan Christmas song, “Fum, fum, fum.” I sang it at the Epiphany celebration at Church of the Sojourners last night. I’m sorry I didn’t get the ‘pastorets’ to eat ‘botifarra,’ a Catalunyan sausage.
On December twenty-five Fum, fum, fum On December twenty-five Fum, fum, fum A child comes in the night So rosy white, rosy and white Virgin Mary’s holy son To a stable now has come Fum, fum, fum.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kant help but post this</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2007/12/08/kant-help-but-post-this/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Dec 2007 02:25:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2007/12/08/kant-help-but-post-this/</guid>
      <description>(Via Crooked Timber)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ser-Venn-Ity Prayer in Google’s new Chart API</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2007/12/07/ser-venn-ity-prayer-in-googles-new-chart-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Dec 2007 15:46:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2007/12/07/ser-venn-ity-prayer-in-googles-new-chart-api/</guid>
      <description>Courtesy of Google’s Chart API.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RemoveSpecialCharsExceptQuote</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2007/11/26/657/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2007 14:35:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2007/11/26/657/</guid>
      <description>Worse than Failure posts about a silly function named:
`Worse than Failure posts about a silly function named:
`
Hah! If I’d written this in Lisp, it would be the much simpler:
remove_special_chars_except_quote&amp;lt;em&amp;gt;ampersand&amp;lt;/em&amp;gt; apostrophe_open_bracket_close_bracket_comma&amp;lt;em&amp;gt;hyphen&amp;lt;/em&amp;gt; full_stop_comma_forward_slash
which is why Lisp is so much better than Any Other Language.
(I tend to write functions that have names that are too long, which is why I thought this was funny. I wonder what the longest function name that I’ve ever written is?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Traveling kindness</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2007/11/22/traveling-kindness/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2007 02:48:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2007/11/22/traveling-kindness/</guid>
      <description>I had a short article published in our local paper, the Kalamazoo Gazette:
 It was New Year’s Eve, and things were finally starting to go right. Our car had broken down outside Forsyth, Ga., on Christmas Eve, and we had had to hitchhike to northern Florida to visit my mother, leaving our car at a garage for repairs. When we got back to Forsyth, the repair shop declared even more repairs were necessary, and we had to ask my wife’s parents to wire us some money.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cucumber curse of the day</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2007/10/29/cucumber-curse-of-the-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2007 13:54:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2007/10/29/cucumber-curse-of-the-day/</guid>
      <description>This cross-legg’d cabbage-eating son of a cucumber!
(Sir J. Jollup in Hone Every-day Book 2, from the OED entry for cucumber.)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More ubiquitous helmet news …</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2007/10/27/more-ubiquitous-helmet-news/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Oct 2007 17:30:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2007/10/27/more-ubiquitous-helmet-news/</guid>
      <description>In more news of our always-wearing-helmets future:
 “This is more a piece of safety equipment, along the lines of a child car seat, than just a piece of athletic equipment,” Ferrara said. From Helmet design Absorbs Shock in a New Way — yet another new helmet design.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Word of the day: desultory</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2007/10/11/word-of-the-day-desultory/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Oct 2007 16:10:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2007/10/11/word-of-the-day-desultory/</guid>
      <description>Acccording to the AHD:
 Desultory suggests a shifting about from one thing to another that reflects a lack of method: a desultory conversation. Pronounced: deSULtory. This is one of those words I thought I knew, but I didn’t when I actually looked it up. It’s a good word to describe this weblog.
 The origins are described thusly:
 [Origin: 1575–85; &amp;lt; L désultōrius pertaining to a désultor (a circus rider who jumps from one horse to another), equiv.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Changing my name</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2007/08/18/changing-my-name/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Aug 2007 22:45:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2007/08/18/changing-my-name/</guid>
      <description>I was born William Alan Fitzgerald. Fitzgerald, of course is my family name, but I don’t have any real connections to ‘William’ or ‘Alan.’ My dad sometimes says I was named after my Uncle Allen, but if so, why isn’t my middle name spelled as he spells it? It doesn’t make sense.
So, as of now, I am changing my name.
I want a name that’s different. Really different. Different all the time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A as in ‘heir’</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2007/08/17/a-as-in-heir/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2007 04:41:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2007/08/17/a-as-in-heir/</guid>
      <description>Phitsjerld’s Fauxnetik Alfabett: (An attempt at the world’s worst phonetic alphabet, on the lines of ‘alpha, bravo, charlie’):
 ‘A as in ‘heir’, B as in ‘clime’, C as in ‘quire’, D as in ‘guest’, E as in ‘urn’, F as in ‘prophet’, G as in ‘bow’, H as in ‘owe’, I as in ‘synch’, J as in ‘genes’, K as in ‘nob’, L as in ‘torque’, M as in ’em’, N as in ‘en’, O as in ‘barren’, P as in ‘pneumatic’, Q as in ‘cue’, R as in ‘caw’, S as in ‘cent’, T as in ‘tee’, U as in ‘oral’, V as in ‘fifer’, W as in ‘right’, X as in ‘whacks’, Y as in ‘gaze’, Z as in ‘phase’.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I am Thesaurus!</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2007/08/06/i-am-thesaurus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Aug 2007 23:34:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2007/08/06/i-am-thesaurus/</guid>
      <description>Synonyms and antonyms and matching terms and words that share a meaning. All these alternate words to choose or substitute why write ‘crying’ when you could write ‘weeping’ or ‘shedding a tear or two,’ ‘blubbering’, ‘wailing,’ ‘choking up and balling,’ ‘sobbing both your eyes out,’ ‘turning on the waterworks.’ I am the Roget I’m Dr. Roget I am Thesaurus Synon-ny-nyms!
Vocabulary dictionary wordy little Frenchman that I am. See how many phrases the Beatles could have made if they’d asked me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>to cat</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2007/06/22/to-cat/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jun 2007 23:07:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2007/06/22/to-cat/</guid>
      <description>It’s always fun to see what obscure meanings of words show up as I do my work. Today’s obscure word is the verb “to cat,” meaning “to vomit.” According the Grose’s 1811 Dictionary of Vulgar Tongue, here are some other ways to say “to vomit:”</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Waxing gibbous</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2007/05/31/waxing-gibbous/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2007 13:05:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2007/05/31/waxing-gibbous/</guid>
      <description>Today’s Earth and Sky discusses a few topics mildly dear to my lunatic heart. They discuss blue moons and time zones.
 When there’s a second full moon of a calendar month, it’s come to be called a Blue Moon. I like the careful use of “it’s come to be called,” since it is a bit controversial what “blue moon” means, and where it comes from. But I think they’re right that “the second full moon of a calendar month” is the most common meaning of “blue moon” these days.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Actually, a little more robot overlordship than I’m currently experiencing would be nice</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2007/05/17/actually-a-little-more-robot-overlordship-than-im-currently-experiencing-would-be-nice/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 May 2007 05:16:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2007/05/17/actually-a-little-more-robot-overlordship-than-im-currently-experiencing-would-be-nice/</guid>
      <description>Sitting down to dinner, I said something like today I wrote a program that wrote a program, and its running righ now. Daughter and wife looked slightly alarmed, and dear wife asked if there were any chance that I was working myself out of a job. I said I didn’t think there was much chance that the coming robot wars were about to begin. Getting back to my computer later, I saw this on the console:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Predictshunz 4 2000 frm 1990</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2007/04/19/predictshunz-4-2000-frm-1990/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Apr 2007 02:53:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2007/04/19/predictshunz-4-2000-frm-1990/</guid>
      <description>K h00t!:
 There will be No C, X or Q in our every-day alphabet. They will be abandoned because unnecessary. Spelling by sound will have been adopted, first by the newspapers. English will be a language of condensed words expressing condensed ideas, and will be more extensively spoken than any other. Russian will rank second.” C,Q–ok! But X? wtf? No haxxors n 1900, imho.
 &amp;amp; Russia? wft? Xhina #2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Attn: Dan Fitzgerald</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2007/03/30/attn-dan-fitzgerald/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2007 22:46:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2007/03/30/attn-dan-fitzgerald/</guid>
      <description>Signs of the Apocalypse:
[Reporting on NCAA tournament pool at Powerset]: Will Fitzgerald is now in the lead, followed by Lukas, then Dave. If Georgetown wins Dave Simpson is in VERY good shape.
Here is the Breakdown going into the final four:
Will Fitzgerald: 78 (teams left: FLA, OSU) Lukas B: 77 (teams left: FLA, OSU, G’Town) Dave S: 76 (teams left: FLA, OSU, G’Town) Richard H 1: 62 Richard H 2: 59 Ryan F: 57 Chris K: 56</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The official syrup and hot sauce of the Montgomery Biscuits</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2007/03/15/the-official-syrup-and-hot-sauce-of-the-montgomery-biscuits/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2007 13:08:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2007/03/15/the-official-syrup-and-hot-sauce-of-the-montgomery-biscuits/</guid>
      <description>Mark writes about serving pancakes for supper for the first time (and claims to be the first evah to blog about it).
And it reminded me how much I like Alaga syrup, “The official syrup and hot sauce of the Montgomery Biscuits.” I have no idea when I first started using (back in Carbondale, Illinois?), but it’s what I prefer for all my syrup needs. Imagine my delight that you can buy Alaga by by the case, only $30 for 12 24-ounce bottles (plus shipping).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Word game!</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2007/03/09/word-game/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Mar 2007 18:11:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2007/03/09/word-game/</guid>
      <description>A fun word game oddly related to my current work: Varun’s word games.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How short the time! How frail the state!</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2007/02/14/how-short-the-time-how-frail-the-state/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2007 16:48:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2007/02/14/how-short-the-time-how-frail-the-state/</guid>
      <description>Death, like an overflowing stream, Sweeps us away; our life’s a dream, An empty tale, a morning flow’r, Cut down and withered in an hour.
Our age to sev’nty years is set; How short the time! How frail the state! And if to eighty we arrive, We’d rather sigh and groan than live.
Teach us, Oh Lord, how frail is man; And kindly lengthen out the span, Till a wise care of piety Fit us to die and dwell with Thee.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Happy Valentines Day, Jane!</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2007/02/14/happy-valentines-day-jane/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2007 04:00:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2007/02/14/happy-valentines-day-jane/</guid>
      <description> Kittens! Puppies! Puppies! and Kittens!  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“rebel without a *” -cause</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2007/02/09/rebel-without-a-cause/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2007 04:16:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2007/02/09/rebel-without-a-cause/</guid>
      <description>Rebel without a pulse, XBox Game
  Rebel without a pause, Hippity-hop
  [  Rebel without a pulse, XBox Game
  Rebel without a pause, Hippity-hop *]3 , Lawbreaker Bush
  Rebel without a crew, rags-to-riches in Hollywood
  Rebel without a buspass, warning: MySpace page
  Rebel without a shul, NSFW Jewcy
  Rebel without a gauze, embarrassing one’s own child</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Useless account!</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2007/02/06/useless-account/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2007 00:44:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2007/02/06/useless-account/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Google Poem</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2007/02/05/a-google-poem/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2007 03:07:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2007/02/05/a-google-poem/</guid>
      <description>This is a kind of found poem Google wrote for me. It’s the ‘common words’ list from kmenno.org, the site for the Kalamazoo Mennonite Fellowship:
mennonite kalamazoo fellowship worship prayer song usa church confession god hymn lectionary opportunties readings songs affiliated community exploring focus forming gather gathered helpful introductions january jesus kmenno life listen love normal opening passages peace revised silence sip soup sundays supper welcome word</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Noble but unparsable sentiments</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2007/01/29/noble-but-unparsable-sentiments/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2007 14:13:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2007/01/29/noble-but-unparsable-sentiments/</guid>
      <description>Mark Liberman, in his usual engaging way, discusses “the tangled history of a mangled maxim” at Language Log.
It was prompted by a statement in Bush’s State of the Union address: “Our work in the world is also based on a timeless truth: To whom much is given, much is required,” which should be (to be parsable) something like “To whom much is given, of them much is required.”
Liberman notes that this eventually goes back to the New Testament, specifically Luke 12:48, which, in King James’s Engish, is: “For unto whomsoever much is given, of him shall be much required.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Infinite will</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2007/01/05/infinite-will/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jan 2007 19:45:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2007/01/05/infinite-will/</guid>
      <description>This sort of just happened today, while initiating a video conference between the Powerset mothership and the Kalamazoo complex (i.e., my basement).
Jeff Shrager pointed his camera at the projector screen, and made iChat full screen. So, I guess I’m talking to myself here. Talk about an echo chamber!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forwords and Backwords</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2006/12/28/forwords-and-backwords/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Dec 2006 20:31:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2006/12/28/forwords-and-backwords/</guid>
      <description>A ‘forword’ is a word in which all the letters are in alphabetical order, with no repeats. Here are the longest ones I could find, using a particular word list I have on my computer (all six letters):
abhors almost begins begirt beknot bijoux biopsy chimps chinos chintz dehort ghosty
If you allow repeats, there’s also ‘beefily’ and ‘billowy’ (at seven letters).
Backwords are the same, in reverse. The longest are (at seven letters):</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Harry Potter and the …</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2006/12/21/harry-potter-and-the/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2006 03:25:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2006/12/21/harry-potter-and-the/</guid>
      <description>… Deathly Hollows.
You read it here, first.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do I want to talk to you?</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2006/12/08/do-i-want-to-talk-to-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2006 15:50:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2006/12/08/do-i-want-to-talk-to-you/</guid>
      <description>This cartoon explains an important fact about hobbies and other activities that require special communication protocols and equipment. You’ll want to make sure that the other people you talk to talk about things you want to talk about and are the kind of people you want to talk to.
I came close to becoming a ham radio operator back in the early 80’s until I realized that what ham radio operators talked about most (at least back then) was ham radio equipment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Snow Day</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2006/12/01/snow-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2006 12:49:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2006/12/01/snow-day/</guid>
      <description>After a week or so of unseasonably warm weather, we woke up to heavy, sleeting rain and promises of up to a foot of snow. School is called off, and probably most work sites are closed (but not for us telecommuters).
It must be hard to live in temperate climes where you can’t experience the joy of a snow day; or, as we say here in Michigan, Snow Day!!!!!!! My brother, the UPS driver, would probably use a different set of punctuation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seth’s fun with lasers</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2006/10/28/seths-fun-with-lasers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2006 02:09:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2006/10/28/seths-fun-with-lasers/</guid>
      <description>Check out Seth’s fun with lasers post, and be sure to click on the pictures. Maybe not the coolest thing ever (that would be recursion), but pretty cool none the less.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Powerset Blogstorm</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2006/10/12/we-way-cool/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Oct 2006 12:00:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2006/10/12/we-way-cool/</guid>
      <description>We way cool. We loved school. We
Work late. We Code straight. We
Plugged in. We Bloggin. We
Balloon. We Show soon.
(with apologies to G. Brooks).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>White and nerdy</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2006/10/08/white-and-nerdy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2006 02:35:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2006/10/08/white-and-nerdy/</guid>
      <description>How White and Nerdy Are You?
(At least I only took a white and nerdy quiz; didn’t make it up.)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AARP card arrives…</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2006/10/03/aarp-card-arrives/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2006 19:26:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2006/10/03/aarp-card-arrives/</guid>
      <description>OK, so we decided to join AARP…it’s cheap, and has some good benefits. Our cards arrived today, and I’m a little worried. It says, “Expiration: Sep 2009.”</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Earworm</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2006/10/01/earworm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2006 11:51:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2006/10/01/earworm/</guid>
      <description>(made with commix beta 1.0; commix art by Fay Ryu).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kids tried this at home</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2006/09/28/kids-tried-this-at-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2006 02:08:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2006/09/28/kids-tried-this-at-home/</guid>
      <description>For Jane’s science class, we performed a science experiment at home (She is studying the scientific method again). Because Bess works with peppers, we designed a simple experiment to see which part of an Anaheim pepper is the hottest: the seeds, the flesh, the placenta or the stem. Bess carefully cut a small piece of the flesh and the placenta (she put the stem aside) about the size of a seed for each of us.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Powar(&#43;) law</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2006/09/20/powar-law/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2006 18:58:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2006/09/20/powar-law/</guid>
      <description>This just in: Results from International Talk Like a Pirate Day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plumnomics</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2006/08/26/plumnomics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Aug 2006 13:21:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2006/08/26/plumnomics/</guid>
      <description>With the demotion of Pluto to a dwarf planet, there are reports that a new mnemonic is required to recall the order of the nine–er, wait, only eight–planets. In fact, Jason Kottke sponsored a mnemonics contest. Kottke is one of the first generation bloggers, along Meg Hourihan. They were the subject of a New Yorker article early on, as well as an update recently when they got married. Kottke doesn’t write very much about himself, though, so I was pretty sure my entry wouldn’t win, but I still like it very much:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Liberty Caskets: Lease or Buy</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2006/08/24/liberty-caskets-lease-or-buy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2006 12:46:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2006/08/24/liberty-caskets-lease-or-buy/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Goggles</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2006/08/05/google-goggles/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Aug 2006 11:48:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2006/08/05/google-goggles/</guid>
      <description>Way cool flight-sim that uses Google maps for background: Goggles. (via rw).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neighbours online!</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2006/07/16/neighbours-online/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2006 04:11:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2006/07/16/neighbours-online/</guid>
      <description>The Canadian National Film Board has put lots of their short films online, including a childhood favorite: Neighbours. (via bb).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My repeatedly brave</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2006/06/17/my-repeatedly-brave/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jun 2006 15:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2006/06/17/my-repeatedly-brave/</guid>
      <description>Mark Liberman (to whom I emailed about Zonker’s use of ‘my brave‘), wrote about ‘My adjective‘ on Language Log. As usual, he has interesting things to say. He points out that
 One small issue is that second-person forms like “your idiotic” are homophonous with the corresponding clausal forms “you’re idiotic” etc. But that sort of ambiguity between innovation and conservatism may be an advantage.
 I began to wonder whether complex adjectival phrases will eventually be allowed in “My ___” forms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gifts I’m unlikely to get for Father’s day</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2006/06/15/gifts-im-unlikely-to-get-for-fathers-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jun 2006 13:29:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2006/06/15/gifts-im-unlikely-to-get-for-fathers-day/</guid>
      <description>(All from Father’s Day ads in this morning’s San Francisco Chronicle):
 Breitling Chronomat Evolution watch (Tourneau, $5,235) Spring sportswear for misses (Macy’s, 30% off) 5 gallons of paint (Lowe’s, $10 off) 4 piece carpet set (Sears, $9.99) Toddler’s sundress (Kohl’s, 50% off) Howard Stern show subscription (Sirius, $12.95 per month)  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Glossary for the confused</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2006/05/28/glossary-for-the-confused/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 May 2006 18:48:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2006/05/28/glossary-for-the-confused/</guid>
      <description>Need to know more about Christianity and its many ‘technical’ terms? holyoffice explains it all to you:
 The Emerging Church: This is a term that refers to churches attended exclusively by white people in their 20s and 30s who have at least one tattoo or body piercing. Their distinguishing characteristics are a refreshing, “up to date” interpretation of Christianity, and a reluctance to directly answer questions. He also explains the code from Vinci:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Happy 06-05-04T03:02:01&#43;00!</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2006/05/04/happy-06-05-04t03020100-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2006 07:02:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2006/05/04/happy-06-05-04t03020100-4/</guid>
      <description>Happy 06-05-04T03:02:01+00!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Qual question: What is the worst poem?</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2006/04/19/qual-question-what-is-the-worst-poem/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2006 01:39:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2006/04/19/qual-question-what-is-the-worst-poem/</guid>
      <description>Daughter Jane has an assignment to “savor [the] awfulness” of a very bad poem, so we got to read some one unto another. Seamus Cooney has a Bad Poetry page, but there isn’t much that’s truly awful there, except perhaps, Kalamazoo (bottom of page) by JB Smiley:
Kalamazoo
On the outskirts are celery marshes Which only a few years ago Were as wet as a drugstore in Kansas And as worthless as marshes could grow, Well some genius bethought him to drain them And to add in a short year or two About eighty-five thousand dollars To the income of Kalamazoo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Luke, soy tu madre</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2006/04/14/luke-soy-tu-madre/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Apr 2006 02:28:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2006/04/14/luke-soy-tu-madre/</guid>
      <description>Fun song, randomly discovered: Luke, soy tu madre by Ultraplayback. Quiero bailar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boats against the current</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2006/04/12/boats-against-the-current/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2006 05:02:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2006/04/12/boats-against-the-current/</guid>
      <description>I used F. Scott (no relation) Fitzgerald’s last line from the Great Gatsby,
 So we beat on, boats against the current, borne back ceaselessly into the past. in an email note today, basically as an excuse for why something I’ve been working on probably won’t be finished on time, and why we should probably revert to an older version. This is just one of the many advantages of a sort-of liberal arts undergraduate degree: better sounding excuses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Countdown!</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2006/04/05/countdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2006 07:02:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2006/04/05/countdown/</guid>
      <description>Don’t pay attention to those americocentrics who think today is interesting because it contains 1:02:03 4-5-6. Wait till the 4th of May, when at the tone, the time will ISO-ficially be:
06-05-04T03:02:01+00</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ser-Venn-Ity prayer</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2006/03/28/ser-venn-ity-prayer/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2006 19:51:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2006/03/28/ser-venn-ity-prayer/</guid>
      <description>Based on something Samantha Cook wrote. Update: Samantha Cook linked to my drawing!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bureaucracy</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2006/03/15/bureaucracy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Mar 2006 16:03:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2006/03/15/bureaucracy/</guid>
      <description>Even though I work at a large government agency, my work life is remarkably free of bureaucracy. Even once in a while, though, bureaucracy brings a smile. I just had an expense report sent back to me because the mileage reimbursement amount on my form was incorrect; it was temporarily raised in the months following Katrina, apparently, but it’s gone back to the old amount.
However, I didn’t claim any mileage reimbursement; but pointing out that:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“Baby Got Book”</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2006/03/08/baby-got-book/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Mar 2006 16:07:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2006/03/08/baby-got-book/</guid>
      <description>Baby Got Book–“and if you’re Catholic, there’s even more!”</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sherbat</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2006/03/01/sherbat/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2006 02:45:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2006/03/01/sherbat/</guid>
      <description>Bess and I played Scrabble (er, make that Scrabble ™ brand crossword game) tonight, but we didn’t have a dictionary so we had to use our ‘internal’ ones. I passed on a bingo, because I wasn’t quite sure whether ‘li’ was a word (I thought it was, but wasn’t confident enough to force the issue). It is a word, and I even remembered the meaning correctly: a Chinese unit of distance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dumb trucks</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2006/02/23/dumb-trucks/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2006 15:29:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2006/02/23/dumb-trucks/</guid>
      <description>From the Kalamazoo FreeCycle list:
 I am looking for a kids table so my grnadsons can do art activities while they are at my house. Also would like to see if anyone out there has any used chuck the dumb truck items as the 3 year old is just nuts about them and they are very hard to find. (Emphasis added). Not all that common, but it shows up: “dumb trucks” at Google, at Yahoo!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Makink zie roundss</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2006/02/20/makink-zie-roundss/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2006 13:36:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2006/02/20/makink-zie-roundss/</guid>
      <description>Berlitz Improve your English video. (Thanks, Dean &amp;amp; Walt).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ceci n’est pas un card</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2006/02/13/ceci-nest-pas-un-card/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2006 22:01:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2006/02/13/ceci-nest-pas-un-card/</guid>
      <description>Happy Valentine’s Day, Bess</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>eBay: EVIL KILLER ROBOT (seeks to destroy humanity) (item 7588933294 end time Feb-17-06 22:55:49 PST)</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2006/02/13/ebay-evil-killer-robot-seeks-to-destroy-humanity-item-7588933294-end-time-feb-17-06-225549-pst/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2006 17:56:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2006/02/13/ebay-evil-killer-robot-seeks-to-destroy-humanity-item-7588933294-end-time-feb-17-06-225549-pst/</guid>
      <description>eBay: EVIL KILLER ROBOT (seeks to destroy humanity) (item 7588933294 end time Feb-17-06 22:55:49 PST) Heh: “You are bidding on the very best, most psychotic killer robot ever devised by man.” (via robots.net).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Showers of Blessings: The [non-offensive] 23d Psalm</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2006/01/26/showers-of-blessings-the-non-offensive-23d-psalm/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2006 22:21:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2006/01/26/showers-of-blessings-the-non-offensive-23d-psalm/</guid>
      <description>Heh: The [non-offensive] 23d Psalm</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ways from Sunday</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2006/01/26/ways-from-sunday/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2006 06:44:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2006/01/26/ways-from-sunday/</guid>
      <description>There might be a googolplex ways from Sunday to make a list like this: Two ways from Sunday–the universe fails me. Three ways from Sunday–regular punk band. Four ways from Sunday–how friendship is tested. Five ways from Sunday–Christian punk band. Six ways from Sunday–emo poppy band. Seven ways from Sunday–Short story collection. Eight ways from Sunday–HP fanfic (rated R). Nine ways from Sunday–an errant compass. Ten ways from Sunday–Arena rock band.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mountaineer Whittling</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2006/01/26/mountaineer-whittling/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2006 06:00:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2006/01/26/mountaineer-whittling/</guid>
      <description>I just liked this image (from an essay on Appalachian Music at the Library of Congress website).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pogue</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2006/01/25/pogue/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2006 01:44:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2006/01/25/pogue/</guid>
      <description>Warning: trivial post ahead, involving a dream and the Oxford English Dictionary.
When I was a poor undergraduate student, I had a copy of the compact OED, but I had to sell it to buy food or something. By the time I got to graduate school, Northwestern had online access to the OED. Ah, I thought, I’ll never be without the OED again. But as soon as I left the university, I lost it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leap second!</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2005/12/31/leap-second/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:04:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2005/12/31/leap-second/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leap Second Lovers are Traitors</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2005/12/30/leap-second-lovers-are-traitors/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2005 21:05:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2005/12/30/leap-second-lovers-are-traitors/</guid>
      <description>Leap Second Lovers are Traitors
 Look, look, look, look. A leap second is a denial of everything American, of everything good, of everything moral. Hey, it wasn’t my idea; I was just trying to ameliorate the consequences.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wild: BASIC for Javascript</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2005/12/22/wild-basic-for-javascript/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2005 16:11:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2005/12/22/wild-basic-for-javascript/</guid>
      <description>BASIC for Javascript (Requires Firefox 1.5). Even wierder than than Lisp in Javascript.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nice piece of Michigan bashing</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2005/12/20/nice-piece-of-michigan-bashing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2005 07:51:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2005/12/20/nice-piece-of-michigan-bashing/</guid>
      <description>Three Roads Diverged in a Wood and I, I Took the One to Toledo, based on a MeFi thread the Toledo War. (“Michigan went to war with Ohio over Toledo, and Michigan lost.”)
‘Course, they’re on the other side of the mitten.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brilliant moving video idea</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2005/12/08/brilliant-moving-video-idea/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2005 14:17:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2005/12/08/brilliant-moving-video-idea/</guid>
      <description>see: parasite_large.mov (video/quicktime Object)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gateway drug?</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2005/12/05/gateway-drug/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2005 01:06:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2005/12/05/gateway-drug/</guid>
      <description>It’s hard to believe I’ve never tried it before, but I finally did today, and I liked it. Maybe I’ll do it every Monday, then maybe I’ll try it on Tuesdays, and Wednesdays, and work up to the hard stuff on Sundays. It was fun, my wife turned me on to it. What I tried was pretty tame by her standards–she does the really hard stuff, stuff that takes over her brain sometimes for days at a time before it’s done and she can return to normal life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vs</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2005/12/01/vs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2005 05:39:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2005/12/01/vs/</guid>
      <description>Lincoln vs. Douglas, Red Sox vs. Yankees, Michigan vs. Ohio State, Roe vs. Wade, Consonants vs. Vowels.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A027868</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2005/11/28/a053824/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2005 06:57:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2005/11/28/a053824/</guid>
      <description>Tim Converse reports on recruiting trip to Michigan he made–that is, Michigan the University. He asked the audience trivia questions, including “how many trailing zeros in 100 factorial?”
I remember seeing 100! for the first time:
93,­326,­215,­443,­944,­152,­681,­699,­238,­856,­266,­700,­490,­715,­968,­264,­381,­621,­468,­592,­963,­895,­217,­599,­993,­229,­915,­608,­941,­463,­976,­156,­518,­286,­253,­697,­920,­827,­223,­758,­251,­185,­210,­916,­864,­000,­000,­000,­000,­000,­000,­000,­000
I wondered where all those (24) zeroes came from, but I never took the time to figure it out.
Nor did I have time to figure it out as I read Tim’s post, but I did have a couple of minutes to write a Lisp program to compute n!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New (old) euphemism</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2005/11/19/new-old-euphemism/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Nov 2005 12:15:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2005/11/19/new-old-euphemism/</guid>
      <description>Listening to the wonderfully interesting Cylinder Preservation and Digitization Project, I came across a euphemism that’s new to me (and, in fact, returns no results when entered into Google search, and only one at Yahoo search): “I don’t give a stamp!”</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Live fast, die young …</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2005/11/18/live-fast-die-young/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2005 22:09:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2005/11/18/live-fast-die-young/</guid>
      <description>Live Fast, Die Young – the Short Life of Early Modern German Auxiliary Ellipsis (!)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>file under ‘mildly amusing’</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2005/11/11/file-under-mildly-amusing/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2005 15:52:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2005/11/11/file-under-mildly-amusing/</guid>
      <description>Mildly amusing reviews of the $33k Gulbransen (Beer) Bottle Organ on Amazon.com. (Note: I was not looking for beer bottle organs when I came across this…)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Latest ‘Flap’ : African labiodental practices</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2005/11/01/latest-flap-african-labiodental-practices/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2005 22:03:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2005/11/01/latest-flap-african-labiodental-practices/</guid>
      <description>SIL is reporting a flap symbolic of certain labiodental practices in central and southeastern Africa.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Choose Your Own Career in Linguistics!</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2005/11/01/choose-your-own-career-in-linguistics/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2005 17:02:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2005/11/01/choose-your-own-career-in-linguistics/</guid>
      <description>Choose Your Own Career in Linguistics
Hint: To win great glory, double major in physics, and work on the temporal wormhole project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>If I were a Springer-Verlag Graduate Text in Mathematics</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2005/10/11/if-i-were-a-springer-verlag-graduate-text-in-mathematics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2005 00:46:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2005/10/11/if-i-were-a-springer-verlag-graduate-text-in-mathematics/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt;td&amp;gt; &amp;lt;p&amp;gt; If I were a Springer-Verlag Graduate Text in Mathematics, I would be Saunders Mac Lane&amp;amp;#8217;s &amp;lt;b&amp;gt;&amp;lt;i&amp;gt;Categories for the Working Mathematician&amp;lt;/i&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt;. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt; &amp;lt;p&amp;gt; I provide an array of general ideas useful in a wide variety of fields. Starting from foundations, I illuminate the concepts of category, functor, natural transformation, and duality. I then turn to adjoint functors, which provide a description of universal constructions, an analysis of the representation of functors by sets of morphisms, and a means of manipulating direct and inverse limits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Knock-knock</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2005/10/11/knock-knock/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2005 11:53:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2005/10/11/knock-knock/</guid>
      <description>VERBATIM: Knock-knock
Who’s there?
Objective case.
…</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Doing the Martin Shuffle</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2005/10/10/doing-the-martin-shuffle/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2005 14:52:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2005/10/10/doing-the-martin-shuffle/</guid>
      <description>Fun Peter Norvig post on using randomized techniques to listen to a particular song on an iPod shuffle: Doing the Martin Shuffle (with your iPod). The ‘Martin’ of the ‘Martin Shuffle’ is Charles Martin. Charles was the 2nd grad student of Chris Riesbeck‘s to graduate; I was the 3rd. We both did NLP research, and Charles was my boss for two days (if I remember correctly) when I joined “Intell/Agent Systems,” which now seems like a long time ago.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ultimate Roshambo</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2005/09/28/ultimate-roshambo/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2005 20:49:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2005/09/28/ultimate-roshambo/</guid>
      <description>RPS – 25 (via exploding aardvark).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>lovely typo</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2005/09/23/lovely-typo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2005 11:40:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2005/09/23/lovely-typo/</guid>
      <description>From the /. article: Mini-ITX Computing For Everyone
 No details are emitted so if you are new to Mini-ITX and do not have a clue what you need or where to start then this would certainly be a good place to start.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“as addicting as crack”</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2005/09/20/as-addictive-as-crack/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2005 03:57:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2005/09/20/as-addictive-as-crack/</guid>
      <description>Things that are addicting as crack:
 hate blowing glass federal funding The Facebook Sony PSP Sims Online (also as much fun as dental surgery) the one-click ordering process Girl scout cookies a Japanese restaurant the Harry Potter books NFL primetime playing with knives America’s fatty foods, including Krispy Kreme donuts and Long John Silver’s batter-covered greasy food Everquest (naturally)  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pointless incessant barking</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2005/09/14/pointless-incessant-barking/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2005 14:46:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2005/09/14/pointless-incessant-barking/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Genome Quilts</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2005/09/10/genome-quilts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2005 00:38:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2005/09/10/genome-quilts/</guid>
      <description>Cool, pretty: Genome Quilts by Beverly St. Clair.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interesting discussion on ‘Earth on Edge’</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2005/09/07/interesting-discucssion-on-earth-on-edge/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2005 01:14:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2005/09/07/interesting-discucssion-on-earth-on-edge/</guid>
      <description>PBS – Bill Moyers Reports: Earth on Edge – Join the Discussion not really 🙂</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Found spam poems (I)</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2005/08/22/found-spam-poems-i/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2005 15:29:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2005/08/22/found-spam-poems-i/</guid>
      <description>utensil devotion toast, if whale bivouac and marriage doorman.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>those which, from a distance, look like flies (*)</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2005/08/17/those-which-from-a-distance-look-like-flies/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2005 02:14:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2005/08/17/those-which-from-a-distance-look-like-flies/</guid>
      <description>Daughter Jane straightened out our DVDs today, at her mother’s request. She decided to organize by genre:
 Fighting movies (e.g. Crouching Tiger, Hidden Dragon), Animation (e.g. The Incredibles), Classicish (e.g. It’s a Wonderful Life), Magic (e.g., Harry Potter), Modern Action (e.g., Charlie’s Angels), Princess Movies (e.g. The Princess Diaries), Movies That I Have No Intention of Watching in the Next Millenium (e.g. 2001, A Space Oddesey).  (*) See The Analytical Language of John Wilkins.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neave Lab › Flash Earth</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2005/08/16/neave-lab-flash-earth/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2005 01:57:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2005/08/16/neave-lab-flash-earth/</guid>
      <description>Beautiful</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>There really are Ligers???</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2005/08/11/there-really-are-ligers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2005 18:40:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2005/08/11/there-really-are-ligers/</guid>
      <description>(via kottke).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An earlier era</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2005/08/05/an-earlier-era/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2005 16:10:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2005/08/05/an-earlier-era/</guid>
      <description>
 In the foreground is an OJ379 standard intelligence terminal that allows an intelligence analyst to view incoming data on one screen while using the other screen to view reference data. The equipment is located at the cartographic facility. Location: GRIFFISS AIR FORCE BASE, NEW YORK (NY) UNITED STATES OF AMERICA (USA)
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Waldemar Tzilligif</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2005/08/03/waldemar-tzilligif/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Aug 2005 13:17:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2005/08/03/waldemar-tzilligif/</guid>
      <description>Fun generator of pseudonyms: Générez votre pseudo by Jean Véronis (in French, but English seems to work just fine).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>May every lion tongue be cast down</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2005/08/01/may-every-lion-tongue-be-cast-down/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2005 13:10:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2005/08/01/may-every-lion-tongue-be-cast-down/</guid>
      <description>Mark Liberman writes about an amusing goof that I also noticed in the most recent New Yorker: a prayer that every lion tongue would be cast down, and suggests the New Yorker hire ‘theory checkers’ in addition to ‘fact checkers.’</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Onion | Never In My Wildest Dreams Did I Think I’d Get Bored Watching Robots Fight</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2005/07/23/the-onion-never-in-my-wildest-dreams-did-i-think-id-get-bored-watching-robots-fight/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jul 2005 00:31:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2005/07/23/the-onion-never-in-my-wildest-dreams-did-i-think-id-get-bored-watching-robots-fight/</guid>
      <description>The Onion | Never In My Wildest Dreams Did I Think I’d Get Bored Watching Robots Fight</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Caller id announcement</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2005/07/21/caller-id-announcment/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2005 15:31:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2005/07/21/caller-id-announcment/</guid>
      <description>My phone speaks aloud the caller id when someone calls. Today a friend called from Immanuel Christian Reformed Church, which caller id shortened, so the phone announced: “Call from Immanuel Christ.”</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Palindrome audio</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2005/07/20/palindrome-audio/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2005 13:07:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2005/07/20/palindrome-audio/</guid>
      <description>Listen to the “my girlfriend has a freaking wierd name…” palindrome.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Good Palidrome</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2005/07/19/good-palidrome/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2005 02:56:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2005/07/19/good-palidrome/</guid>
      <description>Place tongue in cheek: Place tongue in cheek:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Canada Day</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2005/07/01/canada-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2005 12:55:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2005/07/01/canada-day/</guid>
      <description>Happy Canada Day! Sing O Canada! at noon PST; Read The Canadian Encyclopedia, take a Canucklehead Quiz.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kimber Shoop</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2005/06/08/kimber-shoop/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2005 03:19:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2005/06/08/kimber-shoop/</guid>
      <description>Here’s a picture of Kimber Shoop, who played the child who grew up to be William Hurt’s character in Broadcast News.
 But, honest. What are you supposed to say when they keep talking about your looks? I don’t even know what they mean — “Beat them off with a stick.”
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Döner vs Gyros vs Schwarma vs Donair</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2005/06/01/doner-vs-gyros-vs-schwarma-vs-donair/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2005 20:03:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2005/06/01/doner-vs-gyros-vs-schwarma-vs-donair/</guid>
      <description>Döner kebab – Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia
 A variation on the döner kebab known as a Donair was introduced in Halifax, Nova Scotia, Canada in the early 1970s. A restaurant called The King Of Donairs claims to have been the first to serve this version in 1973. The meat in this version is sliced from a loaf made from a combination of ground beef, flour or bread crumbs, and various spices, while the sauce is made from evaporated milk, sugar, vinegar, and sometimes garlic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Have Space Suit, Will Travel</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2005/05/28/have-space-suit-will-travel/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2005 03:37:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2005/05/28/have-space-suit-will-travel/</guid>
      <description>Just finished reading–for the first time–Robert Heinlein’s Have Space Suit, Will Travel. It has the perfect Heinlein Golden Age of SF quote:
 I tell you, the slide rule is the greatest invention since girls.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Headlock!</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2005/05/14/headlock/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2005 22:13:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2005/05/14/headlock/</guid>
      <description>Tim Converse participated in a search panel that turned ugly. Tim thought no one was taking picture, but he was wrong.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First composition</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2005/05/06/first-composition/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2005 20:35:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2005/05/06/first-composition/</guid>
      <description>Here’s the first composition I’ve ever done: an arrangement of Amazing Grace, as a Midi file, as a PDF file. These were created using the cool ABC Convert-a-matic tool.
Update: made a minor change to the tune.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google business solutions</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2005/05/03/google-business-solutions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2005 22:30:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2005/05/03/google-business-solutions/</guid>
      <description>Tim Bray writes about how much he hates ‘solution’ as marketing speak. Unfortunately, perhaps, even Google is providing solutions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Booger Borg</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2005/05/01/booger-borg/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2005 15:17:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2005/05/01/booger-borg/</guid>
      <description>Last night for some reason–probably because we stopped using our humidifier since Spring allegedly arrived–my nose started bleeding. And bleeding. And bleeding. After 45 minutes or so, Bess took me into the emergency room, where, thanks to the state of American medicine and good health insurance, I left after a couple of hours with a Rhino Rocket up my nose. I look like a booger Borg. I don’t think I’ll be posting pictures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>European Constitution redux</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2005/05/01/european-constitution-redux/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2005 15:02:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2005/05/01/european-constitution-redux/</guid>
      <description>My favorite section of the proposed EU Constitution (not that I’ve read much at all):
 Without prejudice to the unified spelling of the name of the single currency of the European Union referred to in the Treaty establishing a Constitution for Europe as displayed on the banknotes and on the coins, Latvia and Hungary declare that the spelling of the name of the single currency, including its derivatives as applied throughout the Latvian and Hungarian text of the Treaty establishing a Constitution for Europe, has no effect on the existing rules of the Latvian and the Hungarian languages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gardner museum</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2005/04/28/gardner-museum/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2005 01:26:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2005/04/28/gardner-museum/</guid>
      <description>On advice from Rob Harris, I went to the Isabella Stewart Gardner Museum. Unfortunately, I only had about an hour to visit, since the musuem doesn’t open until 11:00 am, and I had a flight out in mid-afternoon. Still, it was a wonderful hour, well spent enjoying the gestalt of the musuem, famously controlled by Gardner’s will to neither add nor subtract from the musuem’s holdings. The courtyard is delightful; it, and the sight of a stained glass window as I turned a corner, both made me gasp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mary Mac</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2005/04/24/mary-mac/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2005 03:38:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2005/04/24/mary-mac/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been in California for work, and I got to play a bit too–I sang at the first annual San Francisco Sacred Harp singing on Saturday, and I went to Yoshi’s jazz club in the evening. At the Sacred Harp convention I met Mary McDonald-Lewis, who came down from Washington state to sing. It turns out I’ve heard her voice before–she’s the voice of GM’s OnStar in-car voice recognition system. There’s a great fun MP3 of her demoing her voice on her website at marymac.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apex in tha house</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2005/04/15/apex-in-tha-house/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2005 14:12:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2005/04/15/apex-in-tha-house/</guid>
      <description>Apex in tha house (created via HTTP in tha House).
variety of task domains including those listed ask developed by users combines components yes developed by users outside on cognitive architectures qi a more general airspace definition language pdl see
were developed by users outside building debugging analyzing knee manual for more information what apex vary greatly their experience uncut explore autonomy design parameters simulating for teaching and te capabilities for monitoring and sequence of routine free</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My kinda English</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2005/04/14/my-kinda-english/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2005 20:17:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2005/04/14/my-kinda-english/</guid>
      <description>(via Mike).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advances in Human-Machine Interaction</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2005/04/13/advances-in-human-machine-interaction/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2005 13:10:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2005/04/13/advances-in-human-machine-interaction/</guid>
      <description>Introducing Blendie. (via Language Log).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I may be a Unitarian Jihadist</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2005/04/09/i-may-be-a-unitarian-jihadist/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Apr 2005 15:49:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2005/04/09/i-may-be-a-unitarian-jihadist/</guid>
      <description>My Unitarian Jihad Name is: Brother Sword of Courteous Debate. Get yours.
(But I’m a trinitarian).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tradition</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2005/03/30/tradition/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2005 20:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2005/03/30/tradition/</guid>
      <description>I remember that once, when I was a little boy, my Ma was cooking a pot roast, and she started by chopping off both ends of the pot roast before putting it into the pot. I asked her, Ma–why did you cut off the ends of the pot roast before putting it in the pot? It seems to me that you cook pot roast differently every time you cook it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One suppon a time</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2005/03/29/one-suppon-a-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2005 18:43:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2005/03/29/one-suppon-a-time/</guid>
      <description>I member when me an two a my brothers were walkin home late one night an we found ourself in a graveyard. Lookit here, said Dave — this guy lived to he was 87 years old. Huh, I said. I seen a grave a minute ago had a guy who lived till he was 95. Stevie called us over and said here’s a guy who was 250 years old! What was his name, I asked.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>in the midst of business</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2005/03/07/in-the-midst-of-business/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2005 21:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2005/03/07/in-the-midst-of-business/</guid>
      <description>I’m very busy — but John took me up on my suggestion that he’d look cool in front of a BRLESC-II. Also, &amp;lt;brag_alert=”on”&amp;gt;daughter Jane (6th grade) got a 530 on her SAT–56%ile for all SAT takers.&amp;lt;brag_alert=”off”&amp;gt;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Better to light a candle …</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2005/02/27/better-to-light-a-candle/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Feb 2005 17:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2005/02/27/better-to-light-a-candle/</guid>
      <description>Bess says she wants to cross-stich the final version: Better to light a candle….</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Montréal</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2005/02/21/montreal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2005 17:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2005/02/21/montreal/</guid>
      <description>We just returned from Montréal. The main purpose was to celebrate the wedding of our niece Margaret Lipsey to Chris Kassab. They’re both chefs, and the wedding was held in a 30’s vintage restuarant, the Lion D’or. Margaret and Chris planned the wedding (Margaret even made marshmallows for the late night chocolate bar), so I took a picture of her behind the coat check.
I also got to visit friend and colleagues Daniel Lemire and Anna MacLaughlin, with whom I worked at the Canadian National Research Council, which was great fun.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Penguins!</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2004/12/22/penguins/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Dec 2004 16:33:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2004/12/22/penguins/</guid>
      <description>This was fun.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Translating Canadian</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2004/11/19/translating-canadian/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Nov 2004 08:17:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2004/11/19/translating-canadian/</guid>
      <description>The New Yorker has a somewhat amusing application form for disgruntled Democrats who want to move to Canada, which includes this question:
 Translate the following statement: “Cripes, grade thirteen! Here’s a loonie — buy a Coffee Crisp, eh?”Geoff Pullum can’t make heads or tails of it. But (having been a Canadian resident for several weeks and author of The Canadian Quiz, I think I’m on the case:
  Oh my, [You had to attend] a fifth year of secondary education!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Boston] [cream pie] and [Boston cream] [doughnuts]</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2004/11/13/boston-cream-pie-and-boston-cream-doughnuts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Nov 2004 16:05:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2004/11/13/boston-cream-pie-and-boston-cream-doughnuts/</guid>
      <description>I remembered a post by Mark Liberman about disambiguation of complex nominals when I visited a doughnut shop today. The post points out that, when trying to determine automatically whether a phrase like “sickle cell anemia” is (say) sickle-type cell anemia or an anemia of sickle cells — i.e., whether it’s [sickle] [cell anemia] or [sickle cell] [anemia]–you can do something very simple, which works very well in practice: count the number of times “sickle cell” and “cell anemia” occur in a large body of texts, and the more frequent is likely to be the right grouping.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s cool about working for the Federal government</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2004/10/10/whats-cool-about-working-for-the-federal-government/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Oct 2004 17:30:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2004/10/10/whats-cool-about-working-for-the-federal-government/</guid>
      <description>Having Columbus Day off. Grazie, Cristoforo!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>At home with the Munsters</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2004/10/05/at-home-with-the-munsters/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2004 17:21:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2004/10/05/at-home-with-the-munsters/</guid>
      <description>A little piece of my childhood. (via boingboing.)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flubbed his dub (an ubdate)</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2004/09/25/flubbed-his-dub-an-ubdate/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Sep 2004 20:57:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2004/09/25/flubbed-his-dub-an-ubdate/</guid>
      <description>I was at a bookstore yesterday, and came across an American slang dictionary. “Flub the dub” was included, meaning to make a mistake. Google gives more results, including translations of American slang into Korean and Russian.
Via Yahoo Search: Flub-a-dub was a cast member on Howdy Doody. Flubadubya is a screen name on the Democratic Underground. And, finally, it even shows up in the Bible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Too cool zipcode map</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2004/09/22/too-cool-zipcode-map/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Sep 2004 21:37:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2004/09/22/too-cool-zipcode-map/</guid>
      <description>Use the zoom! (via Anil Dash)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“Flubbed his dub”</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2004/09/22/flubbed-his-dub/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Sep 2004 13:03:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2004/09/22/flubbed-his-dub/</guid>
      <description>I was listening to Johnny Cash’s version of “In the Jailhouse Now,” which has the line:
 Well Old Bill really flubbed his dub when he wore a tuxedo to the country club. I did a quick search for “flubbed his dub” on Google, and only this Hindu Unity rant came back. You can find “flub your dub” a couple of times, including this bluegrass song. I assume that ‘flub (your) dub” means make a big mistake; but how did this Southernism get to India?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Petals around the rose</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2004/09/20/petals-around-the-rose/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2004 16:33:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2004/09/20/petals-around-the-rose/</guid>
      <description>A cool puzzle: Petals around the rose. It told me I understood the puzzle after 16 turns (I started guessing correctly on the 10th turn). (Via BoingBoing).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bush and Kerry’s WW II Records</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2004/09/16/bush-and-kerrys-ww-ii-records/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2004 12:28:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2004/09/16/bush-and-kerrys-ww-ii-records/</guid>
      <description>Tom the Dancing Bug: Bush and Kerry’s World War II Records Examined.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
