<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>A Fibonacci A Day on Will&#39;s Whims</title>
    <link>http://example.org/categories/a-fibonacci-a-day/</link>
    <description>Recent content in A Fibonacci A Day on Will&#39;s Whims</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2013 21:34:31 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://example.org/categories/a-fibonacci-a-day/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A Fibonacci A Day: Using Streams and a Fast Memoization Method</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2013/04/13/a-fibonacci-a-day-using-streams-and-a-fast-memoization-method/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2013 21:34:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2013/04/13/a-fibonacci-a-day-using-streams-and-a-fast-memoization-method/</guid>
      <description>Well, I didn’t think I’d write another Fibonacci A Day post — but there’s a great fibonacci function that’s defined right in the Scala documents, in their discussion of Streams.
A stream is a standard Scala data structure which is very list like. Recall that a Scala list has two parts, a head and a tail; the head is a value, and the tail is either the special empty list (Nil), or another list.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Fibonacci A Day: Fibonacci(n) in O(lg(n)) steps</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2013/04/02/a-fibonacci-a-day-fibonaccin-in-olgn-steps/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2013 13:30:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2013/04/02/a-fibonacci-a-day-fibonaccin-in-olgn-steps/</guid>
      <description>I am taking Martin Odensky’s Functional Programming in Scala class, and discovered (or rediscovered) that the Fibonacci function is discussed in SICP (Structure and Interpretation of Computer Programs, the book that Odensky seems to be basing much of his Functional Programming in Scala course on).
Even more interesting is that a Fibonacci function which runs in O(lg(n)) steps is presented — that is, it takes about lg(n) steps to compute the _n_th Fibonacci number, instead of n steps.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Fibonacci A Day</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2013/03/21/a-fibonacci-a-day-overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 16:20:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2013/03/21/a-fibonacci-a-day-overview/</guid>
      <description>The goal of this series was to come up with a general, efficient fibonacci function that goes beyond the typical computer science introduction. The version we developed is fast, efficient with respect to memory, and general. I’d be glad to hear comments.
The Series:
 A Fibonacci A Day — Introduction A Fibonacci A Day — Recursive Version A Fibonacci A Day — Special Pi Day Post A Fibonacci A Day — Iterative Version A Fibonacci A Day — Out of Bounds A Fibonacci A Day — Speedy Recursion A Fibonacci A Day — Golden Ration Version A Fibonacci A Day — Memoization A Fibonacci A Day — Benchmarking A Fibonacci A Day — Extending to Negative Numbers A Fibonacci A Day — Fibonacci in O(lg(n)) Steps A Fibonacci A Day — Using Streams and a Fast Memoization Method   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Fibonacci A Day — Extending to Negative Numbers</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2013/03/21/a-fibonacci-a-day-extending-to-negative-numbers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 12:00:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2013/03/21/a-fibonacci-a-day-extending-to-negative-numbers/</guid>
      <description>We are now confident that the fast recursive version is the best of the algorithms we have explored — it is fast, and can handle large values of the Fibonacci function.
I haven’t been happy, though, with returning a negative -1 when the function is called with a negative number — this feels like a kind of silent error we were trying to avoid in going to BigInts. Fortunately, it turns out that there is a natural extension of the Fibonacci sequence to negative numbers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Fibonacci A Day — Benchmarking</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2013/03/20/a-fibonacci-a-day-benchmarking/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2013 10:30:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2013/03/20/a-fibonacci-a-day-benchmarking/</guid>
      <description>The following table describes the limits of the various Fibonacci algorithms I’ve created during this series. I ran them through a very simple benchmarking routine, and empirically tested them for the maximum size they can handle. Each benchmark was run 1000 times, except the first algorithm, which was run just once — we already know it runs too slow. These were run on a MacBook Air (Late 2010).
Log Recursive (BigInt)0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Fibonacci A Day — Memoization</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2013/03/20/a-fibonacci-a-day-memoization/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2013 10:00:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2013/03/20/a-fibonacci-a-day-memoization/</guid>
      <description>Although the iterative recursive version is stateless, it looks different from the standard mathematical definition. The recursive version is a very close mapping, but it’s extremely inefficient. One way to overcome the inefficiencies is to dynamically record (or memoize) previous calculations of F(n). The idea is simple — if we already know the values of F(n – 1) and F(n – 2), we can simply add them without having to do the difficult steps in recreating them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Fibonacci A Day — Golden Ratio version</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2013/03/19/a-fibonacci-a-day-golden-ratio-version/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 13:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2013/03/19/a-fibonacci-a-day-golden-ratio-version/</guid>
      <description>The Fibonacci sequence has a very strong connection to the Golden Ratio (φ, or Phi). φ is defined as (√5 + 1)/2, or approximately 1.618, and has lots of special properties. Ron Knott has a web page with over 300 Fibonacci and φ formulas. One of these is this direct formula: F(n) = round(φn/√5), where the rounding function does rounding to the nearest whole number.
This gives us a quite an efficient function:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Fibonacci A Day — Speedy Recursion</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2013/03/18/a-fibonacci-a-day-speedy-recursion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2013 13:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2013/03/18/a-fibonacci-a-day-speedy-recursion/</guid>
      <description>We have seen a very inefficient recursive version of the Fibonacci function, and an efficient iterative version. Is there an efficient recursive version?
Yes, in fact. Recall that the definition of the Fibonacci function, F(n) is:
F(0) = 0 F(1) = 1 F(n) = F(n-1) + F(n-2)
What’s important to note is that the recursive step of the Fibonacci formula has two values that need to be accumulated. In the iterative version, the two temporary variables u and v are used to accumulate these values.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Fibonacci A Day — Out of Bounds</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2013/03/17/a-fibonacci-a-day-out-of-bounds/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2013 13:00:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2013/03/17/a-fibonacci-a-day-out-of-bounds/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday’s iterative version of the Fibonacci function is pretty speedy, especially compared to the recursive version. It calculates F(1000) in almost no time at all —
But. The result for F(1000) looks suspiciously low — and odd things happen if we use a different ‘high’ number, such as 100:
As it turns out, Scala’s Int and Long types are always signed, and do silent overflow. Once the number gets to a certain size, adding more will turn it ‘negative,’ and adding even more will eventually turn it positive, but (of course) the number is not correct.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Fibonacci A Day — Iterative version</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2013/03/15/a-fibonacci-a-day-iterative-version/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2013 13:00:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2013/03/15/a-fibonacci-a-day-iterative-version/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday’s Fibonacci function was recursive, but we saw that it was extremely inefficient. Recursive functions typically break down a problem into smaller pieces, solve the smaller pieces, then combine the results into a final result, where “breaking down” a problem is done by the recursive function calling itself on a smaller version of itself. But, as we saw, it’s possible that the number of times this may happen has to be controlled, or gross inefficiencies may occur; this sometimes gives recursion a bad name.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Fibonacci A Day — Special Pi Day Post</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2013/03/14/a-fibonacci-a-day-special-pi-day-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2013 14:03:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2013/03/14/a-fibonacci-a-day-special-pi-day-post/</guid>
      <description>Binging for “Fibonacci” and “Pi,” I came across this page: Pi and the Fibonacci Numbers, which has the nice formula
pi/4 = Σk=1arccot(F(2k+1)) summed to ∞, where F(n) is the _n_th Fibonacci number.
So, if you can compute the Fibonacci sequence, you can compute pi.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Fibonacci A Day — Recursive version</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2013/03/14/a-fibonacci-a-day-recursive-version/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2013 13:00:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2013/03/14/a-fibonacci-a-day-recursive-version/</guid>
      <description>The definition of the Fibonacci function, F(n) is:
F(0) = 0 F(1) = 1 F(n) = F(n-1) + F(n-2)
This naturally leads to the following recursive function (here, as in all of the versions of A Fibonacci A Day, in Scala):
Note that because we are in the world of Scala, we have to declare that we are writing a function on Ints (that is, the Java/Scala representation of 32-bit signed numbers).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Fibonacci A Day Introduction</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2013/03/13/a-fibonacci-a-day-introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2013 01:20:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2013/03/13/a-fibonacci-a-day-introduction/</guid>
      <description>The Fibonacci sequence is the sequence of numbers 0,1,1,2,3,5,8, … such that the nth number in the sequence is the sum of the previous two numbers; and the the first two numbers are defined to be 0 and 1.
The Fibonacci function is a function which returns the nth number in the Fibonacci sequence. It’s kind of a famous function in computer science when people are first learning about recursive functions.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
