<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Education on Will&#39;s Whims</title>
    <link>http://example.org/categories/education/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Education on Will&#39;s Whims</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2006 03:26:18 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://example.org/categories/education/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Stinky buts</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2006/03/16/stinky-buts/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2006 03:26:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2006/03/16/stinky-buts/</guid>
      <description>We had parent-teacher conferences today. This is almost always a discouraging time.
Jane’s teacher showed us a “persuasive essay” she wrote for her social studies class. The students were to take a stand of whether the US government should spy on people to prevent terrorism. Jane’s first sentence went something like this:
The US government should spy on people to prevent terrorism, but they should do so in a way the protects the privacy rights of citizens.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Lego Mindstorms</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2006/01/05/new-lego-mindstorms/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2006 14:03:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2006/01/05/new-lego-mindstorms/</guid>
      <description>LEGO has announced a new Mindstorms kit: the LEGO® MINDSTORMS™ NXT Robotics Toolset. 32-bit processor. program downloading via Bluetooth, new ultrasoniic, sound, light and touch sensors, a developer’s program, Announced availability is Fall 2006, and should cost $US250.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nose to the Grindstone</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2005/12/16/nose-to-the-grindstone/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2005 21:25:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2005/12/16/nose-to-the-grindstone/</guid>
      <description>Just for Daniel: Inside Higher Ed :: Nose to the Grindstone. (Academics work harder that those in industry and much harderthan those in the government).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Racism and the Kalamazoo Promise</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2005/12/04/racism-and-the-kalamazoo-promise/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2005 05:24:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2005/12/04/racism-and-the-kalamazoo-promise/</guid>
      <description>[Belated Blog against racism day essay]
Many, if not most, institutional systems in the United States were explicitly, and without apology, created with racist intentions. Our constitution declared ‘Persons held to Service or Labour’ (that is, black slaves) to be worth only three-fifths of a regular citizen with respect to representation. Educational systems were set up as separate systems for blacks and whites. Housing covenants were written to restrict blacks and other minorities from living in certain neighborhoods.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Woohoo! Kalamazoo Public Schools to offer free college tuition</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2005/11/11/woohoo-kalamazoo-to-offer-free-tuition/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2005 21:23:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2005/11/11/woohoo-kalamazoo-to-offer-free-tuition/</guid>
      <description>Kalamazoo offers free tuition:
 ALAMAZOO, Mich., Nov. 11 (UPI) — Kalamazoo, Mich., has announced plans to pay tuition for any city public school graduate who attends a Michigan college. The deal begins with the class of 2006, the Kalamazoo Gazette said. The Kalamazoo Promise announced Thursday by Superintendent Janice Brown would pay 100 percent of tuition for students who have been in the Kalamazoo schools since first grade with pro-rated amounts for all students who enter by the 10th grade.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Answers to Questions on Unstructured Data</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2005/10/07/answers-to-questions-on-unstructured-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2005 16:40:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2005/10/07/answers-to-questions-on-unstructured-data/</guid>
      <description>Answers to Questions on Unstructured Data asked by my friend Daniel Lemire for a course he’s teaching on IR and unstructured data. (I should have referenced Tim Converse‘s ‘Are you still working on that?’ essay, but it was unavailable today…)
**Update:**Tim says (writing from Seoul) that his weblog is available again, so his essay You still working on that?, which he wrote at Excite before it eventually became part of Yahoo, is, too.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Animated Atlas: Growth of a Nation</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2005/07/06/animated-atlas-growth-of-a-nation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2005 16:17:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2005/07/06/animated-atlas-growth-of-a-nation/</guid>
      <description>Pretty cool: Animated Atlas: Growth of a Nation (via kottke)&amp;gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adults can be retrained to learn second languages more easily, says UCL scientist</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2005/06/15/adults-can-be-retrained-to-learn-second-languages-more-easily-says-ucl-scientist/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2005 12:34:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2005/06/15/adults-can-be-retrained-to-learn-second-languages-more-easily-says-ucl-scientist/</guid>
      <description>Adults can be retrained to learn second languages more easily, says UCL scientist (via Mirabilis.ca). This looks encouraging; still, it’s a small study–the study showed that a study of 63 Japanese ESL students were able to increase their perception of the r/l distinction in English by 18% after 10 sessions. Still, the r/l distinction is notoriously difficult (even native speakers of English end up going for ‘speech therapy’ to learn how to produce the r/l distinction).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trump University</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2005/05/29/trump-university/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2005 22:49:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2005/05/29/trump-university/</guid>
      <description>So Donald Trump has started himself a university, and Roger Schank, who headed the Institute for the Learning Sciences when I was a grad student at Northwestern, is the Chief Learning Officer.
Roger writes an “occasional column” called “Educational Outrage. He talks about the press reaction to some comments he made about the pedagogy to be used at Trump University in [Is Trump Academic?][3]
One reaction from another grad (who will remain nameless):</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>englishdroid.com</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2005/03/03/englishdroidcom/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2005 23:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2005/03/03/englishdroidcom/</guid>
      <description>Much fun about teaching English as a foreign language, as I did in a former life; including a bitter essay that pretty much explains why I stopped teaching EFL.
 After the age of 40, English teachers are burnt-out, skill-less and unemployable, their working lives a wasteland, their future oblivion. Suicide attempts are not unheard of. A former colleague of mine, a charming and talented but fatally lazy Scotsman who was well on his way to drinking himself to death, was recently found in a pool of blood, having tried to finish himself off by slashing his wrists.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
