<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>First mention on Will&#39;s Whims</title>
    <link>http://example.org/categories/first-mention/</link>
    <description>Recent content in First mention on Will&#39;s Whims</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Aug 2010 18:10:39 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://example.org/categories/first-mention/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>First mention: “sanctity of marriage”</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2010/08/18/first-mention-sanctity-of-marriage/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Aug 2010 18:10:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2010/08/18/first-mention-sanctity-of-marriage/</guid>
      <description>First mention in the New York Times of the expression “sanctity of marriage.”
 We cannot be silent on those laws of your country which, in direct contravention of God’s own law, ‘instituted in the time of man’s innocency,’ deny, in effect, to the slave the sanctity of marriage, with all its joys, rights and obligations. New York Times, December 15, 1852, Page 1.
 This is contra a claim in “Traditional Marriage Perverts the Tradition of Marriage,” that the phrase was invented in 2004.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First mention: “Clean and sober”</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2010/08/09/first-mention-clean-and-sober/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2010 17:20:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2010/08/09/first-mention-clean-and-sober/</guid>
      <description>In one of the “Mad Men” discussions, someone asks if it was anachronistic to describe Freddy Rumsen as “clean and sober” in 1963 (from here, I think.)
The first clear use of this expression in the New York Times archives is from August 28, 1892, which has the embedded note in an article about a murder trial:
 DEAR MISS CLOVER: WIll you meet me outside the Canterbury at 7:30 to-night?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First mention: first use of “Ms” in print</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2009/06/23/firsts-first-suggested-use-of-ms-in-print/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2009 01:05:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2009/06/23/firsts-first-suggested-use-of-ms-in-print/</guid>
      <description>There is a void in the English language which, with some diffidence, we undertake to fill. Every one has been put in an embarrassing position by ignorance of the status of some woman. To call a maiden Mrs is only a shade worse than to insult a matron with the inferior title Miss. Yet it is not always easy to know the facts. When an author puts on the title page of a book Marion Smith, it is not even possible to be certain of the sex of the writer, and it is decidedly awkward for a reviewer to repeat the name in full over and over again.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First mention: Sacred Harp</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2008/05/02/first-mention-sacred-harp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 May 2008 01:04:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2008/05/02/first-mention-sacred-harp/</guid>
      <description>Besides what must be a playful reference to a fake invention, the “Sacred Harp of Eloquence,” and a brief mention in a letter to the editor, the first mention of the Sacred Harp in the New York Times comes in a review of Eleanor de al Vergne Risley’s “The Road to Wildcat: A Tale of Southern Mountaineering,” a memoir of her travels; the reviewer says she went to the ‘Appalachian foothills of Alabama and then went on to the mountain country.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First mention: Franklin Delano Roosevelt</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2007/12/25/first-mention-franklin-delano-roosevelt/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Dec 2007 04:31:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2007/12/25/first-mention-franklin-delano-roosevelt/</guid>
      <description>First mention: 1905 for Franklin Delano Roosevelt:
 Mrs. Valentine Hall has sent out invitations for the wedding of her grand-daughter, Miss Eleanor Roosevelt, to Franklin Delano Roosevelt. The ceremony will take place at 4 o’clock, March 14, at 8 East Seventy-sixth Street, the residence of Mr. and Mrs Henry Parish Jr., with whom Miss Roosevelt makes her home. Eleanor and Franklin were fifth cousins, once removed, according to Wikipedia. The first mention of Eleanor was in 1894, in an obituary for her father, Elliott.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First mention: Thanksgiving</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2007/11/22/first-mention-thanksgiving/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Nov 2007 05:45:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2007/11/22/first-mention-thanksgiving/</guid>
      <description>To-day, has been set apart by the State and City authorities as a day of Thanksgiving to Almighty God for the mercies which have marked the closing year. It will, according to custom, be generally observed. We have all had abundant occasions for gratitude to God for blessings received at His hands. It is well to make public recognition of His goodness, and public acknowledgement of our dependencies upon Him for life and breath and all things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First mention: T.S. Eliot</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2007/10/31/first-mention-ts-eliot/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2007 19:28:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2007/10/31/first-mention-ts-eliot/</guid>
      <description>First mention of T.S. Eliot in the New York Times:
 T.S. Eliot of St. Louis, a student in the Summer school of Magedeburg University, arrived in London today with a number of students from Freiburg and other German universities which have been closed on account of the war. “The German officials,” said Mr. Eliot, “showed the students much consideration and helped us in every way, but traffic was interrupted by the military operations and there were few trains.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First mention: Harriet Beecher Stowe</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2007/10/31/first-mention-harriet-beecher-stowe/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2007 19:23:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2007/10/31/first-mention-harriet-beecher-stowe/</guid>
      <description>First mention of Harriet Beecher Stowe in the New York Times:
 Harriet Beecher Stowe, wife of Professor Stowe, of Bowdoin College, and the author of “Uncle Tom’s Cabin,” has received $4,000, as her share of the sales already made of that book. She receives 10 cents on each copy sold, and a Bangor paper says she has been offered $10,000 for the copyright of the book. This is an extraordinary case of good luck or success in authorship in this country.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
